Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Hi, happy Sabbath living man church
family. Um, please put in the chat where
you are viewing from. And if this is
your first time joining us, please put a
one in the chat so we can say, "Hi,
welcome." Um, so obviously this Sabbath
is a little bit different. Um, LMC teens
and youth will be leading out in the
service today and that's why I'm here.
Um so yeah please um share this and um
give us your support and just pray that
Holy Spirit will really use this today.
So for Sabbath school we have other
familiar faces but they are teens. So
Huh?
>> Hi.
Happy Sabbath.
We're really excited to be doing this
for you guys. Um, it looks like we're
Kazia is having
a little bit
of an issue, but I think
um,
what do you say, Michaela? Should we
start out
praying or do you want to just give a
quick overview of what the Sabbath
school lesson is about? Okay, let me
give you guys a quick overview overview.
So, um, of course, we're excited to be
welcoming you to the first ever LOC, um,
youth Sabbath. This is a big,
>> uh, a big thing for us teens because
we've been preparing for this for like
months now, and we're excited to be able
to minister to you guys today. Um, the
Sabbath school, like Michaela said, is
going to be a little bit different.
Um, we've gotten used to doing the
Christian art of war with pastor and
first lady over the past couple of
weeks, but today we're actually going to
give you a um
a sneak peek into our um uh youth
Sabbath night um not Sabbath night,
youth Friday night vespers program where
we study the Bible and we um you know do
freestyle photo theology and just have a
great time together. So, um please
comment and add your contributions in
the YouTube chat. We'll be looking out
for those. Um and today we're actually
going to be looking at um fire in the
Bible. You know, our sermon title today
is forms without fire and um we're going
to be looking at this in Sabbath school.
What is the context of fire in the
Bible? How is God connected to fire? And
yeah, your thoughts and your
contributions and comments. put those
all in the YouTube chat and we'll try to
keep up with them as best as we can.
Yeah. So, like Melinda said, we'll we're
hoping to give you a little bit an idea
of how the team group tends to study
together and share a little bit of it
and yeah, fire. So, oh, there's Kaza.
Hi, Kazia.
>> Hi, everyone. Hi. Happy
So, should we start uh out by reading a
passage that has a lot of fire?
>> Let's start with prayer though first so
we can call down the fire from heaven.
>> Yes, that's a good idea. That's a good
idea.
>> Will you pray with us, Michael?
>> Dear heavenly father,
>> yes. Dear heavenly father, um please
bless us with wisdom, understanding, and
your holy spirit as we study this. um
please uh give our minds clarity and
please show us what you want us want to
show us today. Thank you. In your name I
pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> So
how about
um Daniel 3 and
um I can
start that. Daniel 3.
>> So, Daniel,
>> starting at verse 15.
>> Okay. Starting at verse 15.
>> Um, and then maybe I'll read through 18
and then we can go back and forth a
little bit. Yeah.
Okay. So
now if you're ready at the time you hear
the sound of the horn, the flute, the
harp, the liar, and sultry and symphony
with all kinds of music, and you fall
down and worship the image which I have
made good. But if you do not worship,
you shall be cast immediately into the
midst of a burning fiery furnace. And
who is the god who will deliver you from
my hands?"
Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego answered
and said to the king, "Oh
Nebuchadnezzar, we have no need to
answer you in this matter. If that is
the case, our God whom we serve is able
to deliver us from a burning fiery
furnace, and he will deliver us from
your hand, O king. But if not, let it be
known to you, O king, that we do not
serve your gods, nor will we worship the
gold image which you have set up.
Uh, Kazilla, maybe do you want to take
it?
>> What verse?
>> Starting at 19, maybe through 23.
Uh, Melinda, do you want to do it?
Okay, I'll go ahead for the time being.
>> Um, then Nebuchadnezzar
Nebuchadnezzar was full of fury. An
expression on his face changed towards
Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego. He
spoke and commanded that they heat the
furnace seven times more than it was
usually heated. And he commanded certain
mighty men of valor who were in his army
to bind Shadrach, Mesach, and Abednego,
and cast them into the burning fiery
furnace. Then these men were bound in
their coats, their trousers, their
turbons, and their other garments, and
were cast into the midst of the burning
fiery furnace. Therefore, because the
king command king's command was urgent
and the furnace exceedingly hot, the
flame of the fire killed those men who
took up Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego.
And these three men, Shadrach, Meshach,
and Abednego, fell down bound into the
midst of the burning fiery furnace.
Then King Nebuchadnezzar was astonished,
and he rose in haste and spoke, saying
to his counselors, "Did we not cast
three men bound into the midst of the
fire?" They answered and said to the
king, "True, O king. Look," he answered,
"I see four men loose, walking in the
midst of the fire, and they are not hurt
in the form of the fourth. It's like the
son of God." Then Nebuchadnezzar went
near the mouth of the burning fiery
furnace and spoke, saying, "Shadrach,
Meshach, and Abedneo, servants of the
most high God, come out and come here."
Then Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego
came from the midst of the fire. And the
satraps, administrators, governors, and
kings counselors gathered together, and
they saw these men on whose bodies the
fire had no power. The hair of their
head was not singed, nor were their
garments affected, and the smell of the
fire was not on them.
So, I think we could stop there
probably.
Um,
so
>> you're muted, Melinda.
>> Sorry.
>> Okay.
>> So, I'd like to share something.
>> I'll give my thoughts real quick.
>> Okay. Go ahead. Yes.
>> Okay. Sorry. I don't want to interrupt
your train of thought, but to me, like
I'm seeing like two main themes in this
passage. I see um being bound
and worship
and there is connection between the
worship and the being bound because you
refuse to worship this. I'm going to
bind you and throw you in this fire.
And yet the three guys the three guys
the three Daniel's free friend three
friends are fireproof.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
Wow.
Yeah, I'm definitely seeing similar
similar correlation there. Like um what
the king is having them do is exact
opposite of how
God works and how God wants things to
go. Like so first off, he's telling them
to worship something that's other than
God, other than who God really is. And
then he's also
um how he's acting is completely the
opposite of God. So he's like, "Okay,
I'm going to give you a second chance.
I'm going to show mercy here." And then
suddenly boom. Okay, no, heat up the
fire seven times hotter and okay, just
throw them in. Like it's from mercy to
like complete
wrath. I guess you could say like wrath
with no mercy. from zero to 100.
>> Yeah. It's like how that's so the
opposite of God, how God works where
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> so something something that I really
Yeah. Go ahead, Kazia. Go ahead, Kazia.
um is that we can say that what King
Nebuchadnezzar wanted Daniel and his two
friends to do while Daniel wasn't there,
his three friends to do
is
he wanted them
to not submit to Nebuchadnezzar, but
submit to him and just know that they
were safe in what he would do for them
>> and not say, "Okay, let's just bow down
and this is going to be over. But
imagine if we personally in our lives
bow down to self what others will say
about us or how our reputation or our
character will show that we are easily
we're easily blown by the wind. We don't
have a firm stand.
And you can see with Shadrach, Meshach,
and Abedneo that they had a firm stand.
They knew okay we can't do that or we
can't do this. They had their stand but
if we don't have our stand imagine today
what Bible story would be written in the
Bible if Shadak and Abednego bowed down
to the idol. What what would be written?
It would be a totally different thing.
And so we have to say that having the
the the the
firm stand we can be like Shadik Mushika
and Abednego in every path.
>> I like what you said Kia. You talked
about how you, the king of Babylon,
wanted the three friends to
to feel safe
in his will for them.
And the fact that they didn't feel safe
in his will and they were like, "No,
there's a higher will than yours that we
feel safe in." And get this, we feel
safe in this higher will even
if it means we have to go into a
physically unsafe environment aka the
fiery furnace because that is not a safe
thing for us humans like fire we just
don't mix with that right and they were
like the king wanted them to feel safe
in his will but they felt safe in God's
will and were willing to go into unsafe
places knowing that they were in God's
Wow. I've never seen that before.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. And then because they were willing
and they chose, they chose to
not give in to hold on to what they knew
was right. How they knew God wanted them
to react.
They gave a response that was in line
with God's will. They were able
to get up and walk in the middle of the
fire with God because they held on to
him.
So, and then I love that part about
the only thing that was destroyed
was their bonds
in the middle of the fire. The only
thing was burnt
>> was what was binding them.
What does it say? My chains are gone.
I've been set free.
>> And this is the thing.
>> Wow.
>> Things that shackle us, things that bind
us, bad habits. And I'm going to give
away my sermon here, but bad habits and
and bad tendencies
and just like, you know, all the anti
fruits of the spirit like impatience,
ingratitude, just roughness, all these
things. These are binds. These are ropes
that bind us. And I I don't I want to
bring Samson into here because you
mentioned to me Michaela yesterday when
we were talking about this that
>> Samson maybe you have the scripture
reference when he was bound he and then
he woke up and he snapped those ropes
just like a fire had you know snapped
snapped them or singed them. And I think
when we get in touch with the fire it
will snap anything that binds us.
Yeah. Yeah. It literally says the Holy
Spirit came on him like a fire and what
was binding him, the senus, the cords or
whatever, both instances, they just
snapped like nothing. Like they've been
burnt. That's insane.
>> Definitely.
>> Amen.
>> Well, there are a lot more instances for
>> Yeah, there are a ton. We is there
something more we want to talk about on
this one or should we go on? So, I think
I'd be really interested to see um how
does God identify as fire and then look
at the context that he appears in as
fire. Like we have several things in the
wilderness, you know, with the
Israelites, we have the the cloud of
fire by night and then the burning bush
>> and then um a lot of times God gives uh
fire from heaven as a approval of a
sacrifice.
>> And I'm just getting thoughts here right
now. And then there's also
>> I see.
>> And then there's also on the mountain
when he was giving the ten commandments.
>> Yes.
>> It looked like the mountain was on fire.
>> There was fire.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So scripture reference
>> for
>> Should we start with the burning bush?
>> Fiery. Yeah, let's start with the
burning bush. Where is that, Michaela?
Exodus.
>> Okay, it's Exodus 3.
verse
verse two.
We could start at verse one.
Oh my goodness. Okay. I Oh yeah. H. All
right. So, can I read this?
>> Yes. Go ahead.
>> Okay. I'm just going to kind of read
till um verse six.
Now Moses was tending the flock of
Jethro, his father-in-law, the priest of
Midian.
And he led the flock to the back of the
desert, and came to Horeb, the mountain
of God.
And the angel of God appeared to him in
a flame of fire from the midst of a
bush. So he looked, and behold, the bush
was burning with fire, but the bush was
not consumed.
Then Moses said, "I will now turn aside
and see this great sight, why the bush
does not burn."
So when the Lord saw that he turned
aside to look, God called to him from
the midst of the bush and said, "Moses,
Moses."
And he said, "Here I am."
Then he said, "Do not draw near to this
place. Take your sandals off your feet,
for the place where you stand is holy
ground.
Moreover, he said, "I am the God of your
father, the God of Abraham, the God of
Isaac, and the God of Jacob." And Moses
hid his face, for he was afraid to look
upon God.
Wow.
>> Wow.
>> There's some serious connection there,
though, actually.
Oh yeah.
>> Like
>> I I something I'm seeing is that this
bush didn't burn in the fire the same
like the three Hebrew boys did not burn
in that fire. I'm like oh
>> fire.
The bush was fireproof.
>> It was on fire though,
>> but it just wasn't destroyed.
That makes me think of um
>> Revelation
Revelation chapter 7 I believe where it
talks about
let me check that the ceiling
and there were four angels you know
they're standing at the four corners of
the earth and another angel cries out to
them and says do not harm the earth the
sea or the trees until we have sealed
the servants of God on on their
foreheads. And it's really interesting
because
I don't want to bring Revelation into
this, but later on
in Revelation chapter 9,
>> Mhm.
>> the locusts come out of the bottomless
pit and they were commanded not to harm
the grass of the earth or any green
thing or any tree, but only those men
who do not have the seal of God on their
foreheads. And the context of this, this
is a different study entirely, but
what's interesting to me is that the
green things of the earth are talked of
like they have the seal of God. So this
bush is definitely a green thing, right?
So can green things represent the sealed
people of God is something I'm
wondering.
There is a text and I don't trying to
find it. Oh yeah, Jeremiah 11:16.
that kind of goes along with that. The
Lord called your name green olive tree,
lovely and of good fruit with the noise
of a great tumult. He has kindled fire
on it and its branches are broken. So it
was green and alive
and then obviously if its branches are
breaking when a tree his branches are
breaking it is not doing well. It is
dead. So
>> it is dry green to really Yeah.
>> It can set on fire and not only set on
fire, be burned. When something is
green, it doesn't burn well.
>> Mm- Yep.
>> Yeah.
>> That's why when we have droughts Ooh.
Oo. Okay. When we have droughts, when
we're low on the living water,
we're more susceptible to fire.
And you know that fire isn't only a
symbol for God, but there is also false
fire,
a fire that destroys.
So
you have to make sure that we're we
always are always filled with the living
water Jesus Christ because then the fire
God's fire that consumes and the false
fire doesn't have any power over us.
>> Wow.
>> We need to be alive.
>> Yeah. We need to be we need to be
we need to be filled with the Holy
Spirit like the apostles were in Acts
and um
>> having that holy fire. I'm not going to
get into that because I know we have
that discussion coming up but um there's
a big difference between the false and
the true and you can see that a lot
happening today. And I'm not going to
lie, living in Africa you can see that
every day. There's so many different
pastors who claim that they have that pi
fire and you know, holy fire, holy fire,
holy fire. And you have to really know
the difference because if you're not
careful,
you can either be blessed or you can be
cursed. There's there's both. And so um
just having the spiritual discret the
spiritual understanding
it will help in knowing between the
false and the true.
>> There's only one kind of absolutely true
fire
>> that is lifech changing in a positive
way. But you know both the false fire
and the true fire have destroying
properties.
>> Exactly.
>> The true fire
>> depends on what
>> destroys evil.
>> Yeah.
>> But it
>> harmless to those who are filled with
God.
>> Yeah.
And the false fire
is just another one of Satan's
deceptions. So it is evil against evil.
It's like, "Oh, you're destroying
things, you know." And what does the
Bible say? It says, "A house divided
against itself cannot stand."
So then we know that this false fire is
going to be consumed
>> in the lake of fire at the very end of
the days, you know. And I this is just
like, wow. I I love this. And also, I
like what um Brother Terry put in the
chat. I just I'm just kind of, you know,
eyeing that. And he said, "Hallelujah.
The living water quenches the false
destroying fire." And I think it is
super important, especially now in the
end of days. Like we know that the
second beast coming out of the earth is
going to have fire coming down from
heaven. And we need to be filled with
the living water so that this fire has
no power over us because deceptions will
come. But God is coming too.
>> Reminds me of a fire truck
>> to be filled
with the water to quench out the bad
fire. And it it gives us the truth. It
goes back to us as human beings. We set
bonfires to relax and enjoy in the in
the autumn and have fun in the
fall. But then there are families and
houses. And it can show us if we do not
have if we cannot make that connection,
we can't have the living fire in us
because we either have to have a living
fire or have a a destroying fire, you
know.
>> Yep. Okay, guys. Guys, we I we do have
to go back to uh Exodus, but this is
really making me think of something.
Think about in the New Testament where
it talks about being baptized both with
water and with the spirit which
identifies as fire.
>> Oh
wow.
>> Oh wow.
>> That makes sense why both are so
essential.
>> Yeah, definitely.
>> Yep.
So
we need to be on fire with the right
things, on fire with the true fire,
>> but at the same time we need to have the
water to be drowning out
other fire
>> other than the true fire.
>> Okay. Okay. Okay.
>> Other spirits
drowning out other spirits. Okay.
Should we go back to Exodus though?
>> Let's go back to Exodus
before
in our group, guys. So, every everybody
out there, this is what happens.
>> Rabbit trail. Rabbit trail.
>> Rabbit trail.
>> All right. So, we did the burning bush.
Should we look at pillar of fire? That's
That's next, right?
>> Let's please. Let's do that. Yes. What
um chapter is that in Exodus?
>> Um we have Exodus 13
21.
Let's see.
>> Okay. Kazia, do you want to read that?
Exodus
13 21- 22.
Yeah, sure.
>> Sweet.
>> Okay.
>> And the Lord was going before them in a
pillar of cloud by day to lead them on
the way and in a pillar of fire by night
to not take away the pillar of cloud by
day, nor the pillar of fire by night
from the presence of the people.
You know something back at the burning
bush that strikes me
>> is that
why why did God appear as fire as a fire
that was not consuming the burning bush
to catch Moses' attention? Right? It
drew Moses over. Okay, wait. What is
going on? And then God was able to have
a conversation with him. It caught
Moses' attention here.
The purpose seems like it's
to guide
like so pillar of fire by night that
would be very very visible. The
>> oh yeah
>> idea here is to be seen to be able to
lead and guide the people away from
Egypt. Away from bondage.
>> Yeah. In darkness. Away from bondage of
Egypt towards freedom. Right.
So
God's goal, it seems like, is to be as
visible as possible,
to not leave them, not leave them
stranded anywhere to use this fire to
guide them.
That's what I'm saying so far.
>> Thy word is a lamp unto my feet and a
light into my path.
>> He did not take away the pillar of
cloud.
Wow. No, it stayed there. As far as I'm
aware, it also stayed with them. Now, I
could be wrong. Correct me if I'm wrong,
but it could also I think it stayed the
whole time they were wandering for the
40 years.
And I think that's Michaela. Is that is
that correct?
I believe that's
>> seems like it. I think so.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I I I think that is correct.
I don't remember exactly
>> exactly.
>> Also, wait, wasn't didn't it like move
between when the Egyptians were pursuing
them? Didn't it move between the
children of Israel and Egyptians? So, it
like
>> wasn't it fire on one side and like
darkness on the other?
>> Yeah. Oh. Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay, we have to look at that.
>> Wow.
>> Exodus 14, I think.
>> Wow. Exodus 14:24.
>> Our bodies are
>> Exodus 14
truth. Yes.
>> Wow.
>> Verse 20 and 19. I'm going to quickly
read those. So that's Exodus
19 to 20. And the angel of God who went
before the camp of Israel moved and went
behind them. And the pillar of cloud
went from before them and stood behind
them.
So it came between the camp of the
Egyptians and the camp of Israel. Thus
it was a cloud and darkness to one, and
it gave light by night to the other, so
that one did not come near the other all
that night.
>> Wow.
>> Oh my goodness. Wow.
That's just amazing. That's just
mindblowing.
>> How can you have darkness on one side
and light on the other?
>> And something that I do want to like I
do want to talk about.
>> Exactly. but also how it's being
perceived. Number one, but also God gave
the Egyptians
chance and chance and chance and chance
and chance again. And
what did Pharaoh say? He said, "Who is
Yahweh?"
He's like, "Ah,
we don't we don't care. This is not
important." Like,
>> we have our own gods. They felt safe in
the will of their god.
Oh, wow.
But then actually this is just
immediately making me think of
>> the first story we looked at. There's
the king and he is completely going
against God, right?
>> Uhhuh.
>> But he was he was given a lot of chances
and here
>> he saw he saw for himself
what the fire did in that story or what
happened to the people who chose to rely
on God.
And at the end of that story, he's
going, "Wow, okay, there is no god like
Yahweh." Before he'd been like Pharaoh
going, "What god can deliver you from my
hand?"
>> But
>> yes, that's took that opportunity.
>> Whereas the Egyptians saw, they saw all
plagues. They saw how the uh Israelites
were protected
and they still went hunting them.
Okay, I'm sorry. I just realized
something.
>> I just realized something. Okay,
>> what?
>> So, you know how those
warriors who were binding Isaac, not
Isaac, Shadrach, Mishach, and Abedneo,
they fell down dead when they were faced
with the fire. Whereas the Hebrew boys,
they went in and they did not get
burned. Okay. Oo. Okay. Okay.
You know, the Israelites went through
the Red Sea. They went through the
water.
The Egyptians,
>> they got taken out by the water.
And the Hebrews were all right going
through.
I did not see that before.
>> Wow.
>> Wow. Wow. Okay. Moment of silence. Can I
just say something on that right there?
>> Yeah.
Um, you know, that is just powerful. The
Isla, the water,
the living water.
>> Can I Can I say something here?
>> Um, if y'all want to like look this up
for all of you in the chat, Isaiah
43:2.
Isaiah 43:2 that says,
I'm reading from the New King James
Version, when you pass through the
waters,
I will be with you
and through the rivers,
they shall not overflow you.
When you walk through the fire,
you shall not be burned,
nor shall the flame scorch you.
Guys, that this is this is one of God's
explicit promises. He says, "Whether
fire or water,
>> these two elements that are in
opposition to each other,
>> you will not be hurt going through
either one."
>> Yeah.
>> Michaela's mind blown.
>> Yes, I see.
Okay, I'm speechless. Wow.
No. Yeah, it seems like Okay, this might
be off a little bit, but I do want to
comment. God really likes contrast. He
likes a bit of drama, honestly. I mean,
so
fire in darkness,
um, a unconsumed
unconsuming fire
and then
being able to
survive
and thrive through both water and fire.
Like
it doesn't get more dramatic than that.
>> No, it doesn't. I like um Nicole Curtis
in the YouTube chat. She said, "Death by
water or cleansed by water. The choice
is ours."
Oh yeah.
>> Die in the water like the Egyptians or
get cleansed in the water like the
Hebrews. And for them that was a symbol
of baptism. So,
and then we have the flood first before
the Okay. Okay. This is Wow.
>> That's coming.
>> Wow.
>> Oh,
okay.
>> Only those in the ark
are going to make it through that water.
We're safe.
Only those in the ark
with the shak.
>> And then what did what happened right
after what happened right after the
flood? Sacrifice.
>> Noah built an altar.
>> Sacrifice.
>> The fire.
>> Oh wow.
Again. Yeah. Water and fire. Yeah. This
is a this is a a a
what do you call it? This is a a a duo
that you see like all through scripture.
It's like okay fire water fire water.
It's funny because these two elements
like fire water quenches fire. Like fire
can't exist where water is.
>> But Jesus is like in Hebrews I think
it's 124.
Hebrews 12:4. Don't quote me. But our
God is a consuming fire.
And then Jesus says, "I'm the water of
life."
>> Hebrews 12:29.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah, it you would think that is such a
an oxymoron like uh
how can he be both
water lifegiving and consuming fire?
But it it's both. then they're not in
opposition to each other. They
collaborate somehow. And no one but God
could do that.
>> And sometimes and and um someone in the
chat just recently in the YouTube chat,
they said um sometimes wildfires are
good for nature. Like they actually
promote growth and they promote new
life. And that just makes me think,
okay, when self is cut out by the fire,
then we need the water so we can begin
growing as a new Christian.
I don't know.
>> Wow,
>> that's such a good point. That is very
such a good point. And um um I remember
I remember here in Africa in the
Serengeti, they burned the whole thing
down. And uh the first time I ever
passed there, I was like, "Mom, mom,
mom, stop the car. There's a fire. What
are they doing? Like there's no food for
the animals and all of that." And my mom
told me, you know, they're burning so
that new grass can grow so the animals
can have food to eat.
And you know, God does that for us. He
may bring us a trial that will burn us
down and then all of a sudden he pours
the living water on us and then we just
blossom like like we blossom like we've
never seen before
>> more plentifully than we could have ever
imagined.
>> Yeah.
>> Wow.
You know, actually, I think that really
goes along with the next instance in the
Exodus where there's the mountain and
there's the sanctuary with fire.
>> I think that actually really goes
>> Yeah.
Can you uh what's the scripture
reference for that?
>> Yeah, I'm working on it. Um
>> the mountain of fire. Where exactly is
that? Um, when the
>> I think it should be
I think it should just be Exodus 2
>> or 19. Let's see.
>> Ex
I think Exodus 20. Um yeah, it is Exodus
20 when um
I think that's it where the people um
yeah, Exodus 20 is the ten commandments
and Exodus 19 is where we have the
mountain turning like not turning into
fire but looking like fire. We have
Exodus 19:18.
Now Mount Si was completely in smoke
because the Lord descended upon it in
fire. Its smoke ascended like the smoke
of a furnace and the whole mountain
quakd greatly.
>> Wow. I can I I really don't want to keep
bringing prophecy into this, but
>> no,
>> there is you do
>> another a counterfeit
fire fiery mountain.
>> Remember Babylon where God says in
Isaiah, I'm going to make you a burnt
out mountain and I'm going to roll you
off into the cliffs.
And what what happened of the Lord?
>> God gave the Israelites the Ten
Commandments on this fiery mountain.
>> He made a covenant with
>> strange times and laws. He made a
covenant with them. Oh wow.
>> Are we seeing a pattern
>> where in the end someone's going to try
to make a
>> I'm seeing something. My eyes are
opening.
Wow.
>> Do I have to be more clear? Am I too
vague?
>> Keep going. Keep going. Keep going.
Okay.
>> Keep going.
>> Okay. This mountain is rolled off
off the cliffs. And you remember what
Jesus said about anyone who causes one
of these little ones to stumble. It
would be better for them to have a
millstone hung around their neck and for
them to be thrown into the sea.
Let me let me check the YouTube chat. Is
anything clicking for people?
>> I I'm seeing it. I'm seeing the
counterfeit mountain and how they're
making a covenant,
making new laws,
>> counterfeit laws to God's and laws.
>> Yeah,
>> it is so powerful.
>> And God's like, "No, no, you you can't
do this. I'm gonna toss you into the
sea.
You can't do this.
>> Can't go any more deeper than that. It's
so clear.
>> I'm checking the chat.
>> Michaela, what are you thinking?
Michaela, what are you thinking?
>> I'm going back to the original story
with Nebuchadnezzar.
Are you seeing something? Where
>> I'm seeing something. Okay. I'm seeing
something.
>> Who is going to be destroyed by the fire
when
there's the choice about who to bow down
to?
There were two things destroyed by that
fire. Number one. Mhm. The military
force that was casting them into the
fire.
And number two,
okay, girl, girls, sorry,
the force that was binding them
by command of the king.
And instead of the Hebrews being burnt
up,
that was destroyed
and God appeared in the midst of the
fire with them. This is really
>> really close to like the death decree in
the end of times. It's like, "All right,
you're you're not going to bow down to
the image of the beast, so we're just
going to like unal alive you."
And God's like, "Okay, no, no, no.
And he appears with us. Second coming
>> in that fiery trial with us.
>> I don't know.
>> Before Michaela,
>> go ahead.
Uh
>> oh.
>> You right in. Can I say
>> I think I got knocked out. Sorry.
>> Oh, you're back. You're back.
>> That second Yeah, I'm back. Um, that
second
coming is really power.
>> Are you on mute, Cazilla?
>> Okay, I'm back. Sorry.
>> Yes, you're back.
>> Okay. Sorry.
>> Sorry. Technical difficulties everyone.
>> So, my mom played for us story a few
years ago
um about uh there's a group of people I
just she made a story about the end
times and then put it toward the end.
And because the people did not go to the
Sunday law
and didn't follow it, they were sent to
jail. And when they were sent to jail,
there was this lady and her death
sentence
was to be killed to be electrocuted on
the And right when the guy was just
going to plug in
the the cord to electrocute her.
Jesus came back in this story. And I was
like when when you were just saying this
Melinda about how
Jesus will not let us be burnt in the
fire.
It shows to us that he's always gonna
come through for us. even when we feel
even when we feel like he's not there,
you know, and he's just going to step
right in there and he's going to be
like, you know what? Hey, devil, get out
of the way. These are my children and
I'm not going to let them suffer.
>> Yeah,
>> because I was a story you told though.
>> And so he's just going to come and save
us. And
>> did I not walked out? Yeah. I'm just
saying I'm just connecting it to what
you were saying.
>> Sure. Yeah.
>> And that's powerful. Even when we feel
like
the devil is really trying to
to put us down, God is always there. And
that's something always to remember that
God is always there for us.
>> He said, "I will be with you even until
the very end of the age.
Yeah.
>> Okay, let's keep going.
>> Wow.
>> Michaela, what's the next step? We were
at the mountain in the sanctuary. I kind
of rapid trail us off there.
>> Oh, yeah. Mountain in the sanctuary.
>> I think that
so when Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. I
remember where we were. Um, there was
the covenant in the midst of fire
and then
why I guess we could should go to why
maybe why all of this like why did God
>> Wait a minute. I'm sorry.
>> Catch your attention.
>> Hold on.
One thing one thing. Okay.
>> Yes.
>> All right.
There was fire on the mountain
with the old covenant, right?
Because he was making covenant with
them. But that covenant is now the old
covenant. We are living under a new
covenant, right? Right.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Okay.
So the fire with the old covenant was
external
and the fire with the new covenant is
internal.
Jesus in us, our God is a consuming
fire. The covenant, the old covenant had
external fire. All the sacrifices, you
know, the fire, all the all the um
all the what are they called? Services,
>> everything fire outside.
New covenant, everything fire inside.
I don't know.
Oh wow. Okay. Yeah, I can see where
that's going.
Um but yeah,
what I'm seeing there is okay. So the
purpose in this this old co covenant um
establishing the sanctuary um practice
God says it was to dwell with them,
right? It was to be with them and be
their God.
>> Be their God. dwell with them. And then
maybe we should go to our next story
with fire
in the New Testament.
>> I just want to go around one more. One
more. Oh, girl. Okay. You That's where I
was trying to go. I was like, can I just
quickly insert No,
you turn the fire hose on. This is the
fire hydrant.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Okay.
So
after Jesus died, sacrifices
and temple services, they didn't need to
be done anymore because Jesus, the
sacrificial lamb had been slain for us.
So now
the external fire, fire on the mountain,
fire in the services from the old
covenant moved to inside us. Remember
the fire hovered above them individually
>> and this power
remember you'll be baptized in the
water. No, what did you say Michaela?
With the spirit and fire.
>> Yeah. Baptized by water and the spirit.
>> He will baptize you with water and the
spirit and then also the spirit and
fire. So now this fire is working
internally. It's cleansing the
selfishness, the root of the problem.
It's taking it out.
>> Yeah. Matthew 3:11, I indeed baptize you
with water unto repentance, but he who
is coming after me is mightier than I,
whose sandals I am not worthy to carry.
He will baptize you with the Holy Spirit
and fire.
>> Mhm. Someone in the chat said that the
only change is the location of the fire.
And yes, I I I agree 100%. Instead of
the fire being external, the fire is now
internal
inside us.
What does um Jesus say in Matthew? I
think he says it, but I could be wrong.
He says
um so let your light so shine before
men.
And what what do we know the light in
the lamp? Thy word is a lamp unto my
feet and a light into my path. You know,
we're supposed to God wants to write the
law, his words on our heart.
Do you kind of see where I'm going? You
see where I'm going?
>> Yeah.
>> If your word lamp is my feet and a light
unto our path, and he wants to write his
words in our heart, then the fire is
suddenly internal
and cleansing us from all
unrighteousness. I don't know. I don't
know.
>> Yeah, that's two things fire seems to
do. Fire purifies.
It destroys. It destroys sin. Sin can't
be in this perfect fire. But then it
also gives light. It catches attention
from our attention and it reveals the
truth. It stands out in the middle of
darkness as a pillar of fire and leads
and guides away.
>> I have to say something. Somebody in the
chat. Somebody in the chat said, um,
Mooney P6026,
I'm shouting you out because you said,
"We became the temple, so God lives in
us now."
I Yeah, definitely internal fire there.
Remember when Solomon dedicated his
temple and the smoke of the Lord filled
the whole thing? So, the Levites weren't
even able to minister there.
God wants to fill this temple.
>> This temple right there sitting behind
that screen. He wants to fill that
temple
>> with fire.
>> I'm going to give away my sermon here if
I keep going.
>> Yeah. Be careful. Be careful.
>> I'm trying.
>> Oh my goodness. Oh my goodness. And
someone else just said, sorry, someone
else just said that external fire is
meant to put the internal fire out. So
the false fire that's outside is trying
to put that inside out.
Trials and temptations,
they're trying to battle against the
fire that's inside of us.
>> But we need to be safe in the will of
God, just like the Hebrews were safe in
the will of God
so that the external fire can't hurt us.
>> Okay, I'm sorry. I'm sabotaging this.
No, no, no. Here's the thing. We We've
kind of talked about this in previous
Sabbath schools studying the Christian
art of war.
We You just said that
the distinction is the will of God. We
ourselves self cannot carry out the will
of God. That's why we need the fire in
us. this Holy Spirit fire in us to be
carrying that out.
And that
that spirit fire destroys any other kind
of
any misrepresentation. First off, these
external fires and also our personal
attempts
at carrying out this will. It destroys
anything to do with self. Should we um
go to
>> Let's do it.
>> Romans 8 9 and 10 and 13.
Romans 8 verse 9 through 10 13.
Um, I'll go ahead and read. But you are
not in the flesh, but in the spirit. If
indeed the spirit of God dwells in you.
Now, if anyone does not have the spirit
of Christ, he is not his. And if Christ
is in you, the body is dead because of
sin. For the spirit is life because of
righteousness.
And then down to 13.
For if you live according to the flesh,
you will die. But if by the spirit you
put to death the deeds of the body, you
will live.
>> I'm going to have to keep my mouth shut
because this is literally the core of my
sermon.
>> Oh dear. Okay. Uh tell me want me to
stop.
>> Excuse me.
>> Tell me to stop if you need to. Tell me
to stop if you need to.
>> Go ahead. I need to
>> Okay. Okay, your perspective is
valuable.
>> Okay. Um,
so we have we have all these stories. We
have
Neb the story with Nebuchadnezzar and
the three Capri boys where
they would not give up on their idea of
who God was. They would not give up on
serving only God, not bowing down to
these false false things. And they were
able to walk in the middle of fire with
God.
Then we have the burning bush, the
pillar of fire and the whole sanctuary
system of God catching our attention,
leading and guiding and protecting us
through the wilderness
and wanting to dwell with us.
Wanting to dwell with us.
And then we have God wanting to dwell in
us.
as fire as purifying
lightgiving
fire.
Uh, is Kazya here?
Kazya is I think she Yeah, she's here.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay.
>> Sorry.
>> So, those are some of my summing up
thoughts. You guys talk.
>> Okay. I can because yeah, I'm really
interested in hearing what you have to
say because
>> if I say something
>> about about what exactly because I got
knocked out so I didn't exactly hear the
thought.
>> We're kind of going back over all the
stories we've mentioned. King
Nebuchadnezzar,
the burning bush, the sanctuary, the
mountain,
Jesus in us, the fire,
any thoughts,
>> and everybody else listening, please put
your thoughts and your connections. Put
them in the chat. I'm keeping an eye on
the chat.
>> I will shout you out. Um
Um I can just say there's such a
powerful connection. There's a very
powerful connection there because we're
coming from the Old Testament to the New
Testament and we're kind of finishing it
up, right? And we're starting where
Jesus started with them in the mountain
and in the sanctuary
and everywhere else where he was and
coming to where he finally finishes up
the sanctuary and now the sanctuary
lives in us. You know, you know he still
is.
>> Don't you know that you're a temple of
the Holy Spirit?
>> Exactly. Don't you know you are a temple
of the living God? And that shows us
that even if we um think that the
sanctuary is not in us, it is in us
because we can see in Acts how the
disciples the fire came upon them. And
that doesn't have to mean that there was
a fire inside them internally, but it
was showing an example of the fire in
them that was internally
because it shows us that he was living
in them. And from then on, they no
longer needed to go to the sanctuary and
give the sacrifices.
They just needed to pray and just know
God was in them internally and that he
could hear them spiritually.
And him living in us gives us the
opportunity to fight self again and be
able to be cleansed with the living
water and be able to
douse off the counterfeit fire with the
living water. Him living in us gives us
that opportunity. And if it wasn't for
him living in us, where would we be
today? Where would we be today? So
connecting all of those together, it
shows us that Christ from the beginning
up to the end of time, he will always
>> live in us. He will always be our fire.
That's what I can say about that.
Wow.
Okay. I was just thinking about
something else
we've talked about. We were not planning
on talking about water at all. that just
happened.
So that that was awesome.
But
something I'm saying the goal kind of
the goal here. So the ultimate goal is
for God, God wanting to be with us,
wanting us to be able to be in his
presence, in the presence of this
perfect fire
and survive and thrive.
So the process seems to be so the water
and the fire
in the presence of the water and the
fire self dies.
self. Anything to do with self dies.
But at the same time, the water and the
fire are giving life, or giving
inspiration, are giving passion, is
giving light. Light in general, and
helping us just grow and truly see
in our relationship with Christ.
So,
yeah. Yeah,
I'm scanning through the chat here
and I'm seeing um
Hold on, I lost it. But I want to shout
out
Come on. Where'd it go?
All right. I think I lost it.
All right. Well,
>> somebody said,
>> "Oh, I think it was I think Hold on. I
want to say one more thing. Elena Ruiz
73. She said Moses was drawn out of the
water
and met God in the fire."
And I think that's that's a really
profound realization
because as a baby, Moses was taken out
of the water.
He was saved from the water and met God
in the fire.
And that shows the mercy of God because
he didn't have to like Moses was put in
the water to protect him from enemies
and he was drawn out of the water to
protect him from the danger in the water
cuz the Nile has crocodiles. You know, I
used to live in Florida and you could
not go swimming anywhere. Like don't
touch a puddle. Okay, not that but like
you know
there are crocodiles everywhere or
alligators and nuh-uh. Yeah. Taken out
of the water, protected, put in the
water to be protected, taken out of the
water to be protected and then met God.
And then he was able to go and face the
king
and was protected by the fire of God.
>> Wow.
And then it happened again actually
just with a bunch more people
>> walking through the Red Sea going up to
the mountain top to meet God in the
fire. And when he came down his face was
shining.
His face was shining
for all the people to see.
And then
he was resurrected and went to be with
God in heaven.
So
>> yeah, it says that in Isude, I think.
>> Oh, Hebrews. Yeah. New Testament,
>> maybe. I don't know.
>> Somewhere.
>> Somewhere. Google it.
>> Awesome.
>> All right.
Well,
>> all right.
>> Should we close out in prayer?
>> Let's do that.
>> Do you want to pray or Kazia?
Kazia, will you pray us out, please?
Yeah, sure. No problem. Let us bow our
heads for prayer.
Our dearly father, Lord, we thank you so
much for your love for us. Thank you for
blessing us, for taking care of us, for
guiding us. Lord, it is an amazing
Sabbath today. And we pray that through
everything that we have been reading and
studying that you will fill us with your
fire, with your holy fire.
Thank you so much for helping us to
learn more about the fire in the Bible
and that we may learn more about you
through each and every step of the way.
Lord, I pray that as we get ready to go
to the different programs that you will
bless us and take care of us and bless
us to learn more about your word. Thank
you so much in Jesus name we pray and
believe. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> All right. We hope you've been blessed
by um the Sabbath school.
>> Um it was not at all like Christian Art
of War with First Lady and Pastor, but
we hope you are still blessed by it.
>> Um I just want to say one thing about
the sermon. We've talked about the fire
and God God in the fire, but the sermon
is going to be about how to come into
connection with that fire. So, I don't
know. Stay tuned. Definitely.
>> Yes. Do not miss the sermon.
>> Yeah.
Happy Sabbath.
God's holy word declares that the earth
is the Lord's and the fullness thereof.
And though marred by sin, creation still
speaks of the wisdom, power, and beauty
of the creator. God made nature for us
to enjoy. And there's so much to explore
on God's green earth. But only in
relatively recent times has mankind
taken the plunge to explore the deep
blue sea. With the invention of scuba
diving came the wonderful possibilities
of seeing and studying the underwater
world. Scuba diving is probably the only
way to visit another world without
leaving planet Earth. It's nothing short
of spectacular.
But with so much heavy gear, it's
probably the most cumbersome of all the
sports. There are so many things that
are vital in order to have a successful
dive. You need a mask to see, fins to
propel, a wet suit to keep you warm, a
BCD to keep you buoyant, weights to keep
you down, a tank that holds your air, a
regulator that gives you breath, and all
different kinds of computers and gauges
to keep you informed so that you don't
do anything dangerous. It's super
cumbersome, but absolutely worth it.
Now, there are many things you need to
know before you go scuba diving, but you
might find it surprising that the number
one and most important rule is simply
this. Don't hold your breath. Whatever
happens, just keep breathing. And as
long as you're breathing, you can deal
with any difficulty below. You see, the
natural instinct of land creatures like
us is to hold your breath underwater.
So, once our head goes below the
surface, our mind tells us to stop
breathing. And many people find it
difficult to overcome this mind block.
Not only that, but there's so many
spectacular things to see down below
that will literally take your breath
away.
But holding your breath is probably the
most dangerous thing you can do. It
could lead to a ruptured lung, a panic
attack, or an uncontrollable urge to
shoot up to the surface, thus causing
the bends. And so if you ever get the
chance to experience the scuba life,
just remember, keep breathing. And as
long as you're breathing, you can deal
with any difficulty underwater. The same
is true for spiritual life above the
surface. Prayer is the breath of the
soul. And just as we're to breathe
without ceasing, the Bible calls us to
pray without ceasing. You see, when you
breathe, you're both taking in
sustaining oxygen as well as releasing
the cellular waste product of carbon
dioxide. You're receiving that which is
good and releasing that which is bad.
This is the same thing that prayer does.
Prayer is the means with which we
receive God's blessings and unload
life's burdens. It is the avenue by
which we give our problems to God and
that God gives us his peace and his
power. You see, the purpose of prayer is
not to inform God, but rather it is the
means by which God transforms us.
Many people find life so hard because
they're not breathing the breath of
prayer. They are spiritually drowning in
a sea of sorrow, struggling in an ocean
of trouble. When all the while the
breath of prayer is right in their
mouth. So remember, when life is
overwhelming and you feel like you can't
keep your head above the water, just
keep praying. When finances are low and
the bills are high, just keep breathing.
When your kids are acting crazy and your
spouse is acting lazy, just keep
breathing. When the current of your
sinful flesh is pulling you into
forbidden waters, just keep breathing.
Just keep praying. And as you do, God
will give you the wisdom and the courage
to change the things that you can
change. He'll give you the peace and
comfort to accept the things that you
cannot change. And he'll give you the
wisdom to know the difference. And in
every single situation, he will bring a
change in your heart. And when we come
to trust God, both above and below the
water, in the highs and in the lows of
life, he will show us things we've never
seen before. He will do through us
things that have never been done before.
And he will take us to places no one has
ever been before. And finally, one day,
very soon, we will be able to leave this
blue and green planet below to explore
the heavenly realities of God's
wonderful kingdom. And then we'll be
breathing in the very atmosphere of
heaven itself. And that, my friends, is
a world you surely don't want to miss.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Heat
up here.
Heat up
here.
Heat. Heat.
Welcome back living manage family. Happy
Sabbath. Um for those who did not get to
put in where you're from viewing from
before Sabbath school, please you can do
that now. And um if you miss Sabbath
school, please please go back and watch
it. I seriously had an awesome time and
it was literally fire. It was literally
fire.
So, let me see here.
Um, yeah. Also, we have the sermon
coming up in a little while. And please
think about how these two parts of the
service are connected because um we're
hoping that they will
go along with each other. Well, we have
Freeport, New York. Yeah, living around
a church is so incredible how
many countries in the world view living
in a church. It's really insane. We have
Uh Tennessee and Toronto.
Uh we have Jerry in San Diego and Texas.
Yeah. All across the US, all across
North America. It's insane.
So,
um to
see more about what Lyning Mana has
going on, we have literally so many
things going on during the week. both
the teens, both all sorts of groups
going on in Living Mana to fellowship
and just interact, get to know each
other better and grow grow together as a
church community. Um to stay connected,
we have actually a
uh phone number here. You can text Loc
to 8552074107.
And this will just give you reminders
during the week for okay this is going
on now. Um oh this meeting just started
come and join us. And because during the
week we just have so much going on even
when we want to go we can tend to
forget. So this is very helpful in
keeping up to date. Um
we also have Mighty Networks. Smarty
Networks is um especially for those
viewing outside of North America who
can't get texts. Um writing networks is
our way of staying connected.
So that's where all of our smaller
groups are where all of our
all of our members and others interact.
And uh one of the incredible groups that
we have on living mana is MC kids. I
know for my sister that in kids um the
kids group they have a blast. So they
study really deep concepts in the Bible
but all through like the kids lens. So
it's very very insightful really.
There's so many different perspectives I
hear on it and it's mind-blowing for me
and for others and to hear um the kids
come back and say the younger kids say,
"Oh, we studied this and this was so
amazing." So, that's really cool. To um
learn more about the kids group, just
text um kids to 8552074107
or email loose kids at living.urch
and they have Sabbath school at like
11:30 central time. So can come and
check it out.
um for virtual office hours to meet with
pastor and
discuss if you have a question if just
uh need to discuss something with him
you can set up an appointment by
emailing Patrice at living mana.live
live.
Now, we also have since it's youth
Sabbath, I got to advertise teams. Um,
we have an awesome teens group at Living
Mana. For me personally,
teens has been life-changing. Honestly,
I can honestly say it's been
life-changing. I can see how I am
personally growing in my relationship
with Christ. And I am also growing in
that I feel I have a role and connection
to play in the church for myself. And
I also have met fellow youth who are
some of the most passionate and
incredible people I have met when it
comes to Bible study and growing closer
to God and with sharing that that
sharing that passion. So, I personally
cannot recommend LOCs more. Um, and I
also want to say this, today is our
first birthday.
One year ago today was our first Friday
Night Light meeting. So, that um is one
of our current meetings we have going
on. We meet um currently we are meeting
for vespers on Friday night Friday
nights at let's see here 8 Eastern time
um which would be 7 central. We also had
a
uh Thursday morning or afternoon
uh meeting for more study and also for
just interacting as teens and for
closer.
Um so if you would like more information
and if you are a teen or know a teen who
might be interested in checking this out
sometime, please email teens living
mana.urch church for Mortonville.
Okay. We also have our hurricane relief
fund. We are um working with ADRA.
So, if you would like to help aid in
help the people in Jamaica and with all
this destruction going on, please uh
send your uh donation to um 12501 Old
Columbia Pike, Silver Spring
um
and check out www.adra.org.
or and text hurricane to 18552074107
for more info on that.
Um next we have
to a group here on living mana um
business directory to find out more
information about this. This looks
interesting. Um text biz connect b i z c
z c z c z c z c z c z c z c z c z c z c
z c z c z c z c z c z c z c z c z c z o
n ect at living manana.urch.
Uh we also have other groups on living
mana. We have hangouts and this is to
interact
just kind of hang out and have fun I
think more within the church. So, we
have a watch party going on. It looks
like um House of David
happening
happening um on Zoom at 6:30 p.m.
Central time. November 2nd that already
happened November 16th tomorrow and
November 30th. So to learn more
information about this, text hangouts to
8552074107
or you can scan
uh this QR code here on the left side to
join the hangout space in Mighty
Networks.
We also have our glow groups
and
I've heard a lot about these
as a way to connect and just interact.
Another way to connect to interact with
the church family. Um you can sign up on
mighty networks and you can also email
groups at living.urch for more.
Um, another group we have on Living
Manai is GEMS.
Uh, okay. Yeah, GEMS. So, this is our
adult Sabbath school and they meet at
6:30 p.m. Fridays. To get more info and
sign up, text gems to 8552074107.
Um
now to give your tithe and offerings
um uh through to LLC you can go to
Adventist giving click on the upper
right corner there uh to give your
donation and um choose living mana
church and you'll just put in how much
how much for tithe how much for offering
and then you can also
if you would rather mail in a check. You
can do that. Um, just put in um what
part is for tithe, what part is for
offering. You can send that to PO Box
428, Owens, Crossroads, Alabama 35763.
So yeah, um I'm very grateful for this
opportunity to share with you all today.
I'm hoping that Sabbath is and will be a
serious blessing for all of you. Um so
just bow your heads and pray with me.
Dear heavenly father, um thank you.
Thank you so much for living.
Thank you for the ability to interact
and grow together and to share
share what inspires us in your word and
inspires us about you with each other
and with the world.
Please um please spill with your Holy
Spirit and please um be with the rest of
the service uh the prayer section and
the sermon. Please do you let this guide
us and help us to grow and share this
passion we have for you with the world.
In your name I pray. Amen.
Happy Sabbath everyone.
I could feel the ground shake beneath my
feet.
It shakes this rock, even this solid
concrete.
A reminder that the enemy is always
near. A feeling of loneliness, fear, and
despair. The darkness says there's no
way out. No escape, no relief, just
worry and doubt. And when the fire
comes, and it will come, we must remind
ourselves what power lives in you and
me.
I can feel the flames. Do you ever feel
that intense heat? The stuff in your
life that's real and loud and brings
that feeling of defeat. You see, we
always want to know what's just beyond
the flames. What just lies ahead. But
Jesus calls us to something different
instead. To stand surrounded. to stand
amidst the fire and to know that he is
near. To trust that he knows what we
don't, that he is our deliverer and he
will deliver us. But even if he doesn't,
I'll still stand. Even if he doesn't, I
will not fall. I'll count the joy in
every battle because I know where Jesus
will be. He'll be standing amidst the
fire in the flames right beside me. He
is God Emmanuel, God with us. And he
reigns far above because he who was and
is and will be is with me through it
all.
And I know I will never never be alone.
Before
I spoke a word, you were singing over
me.
You have been so so good to me
before I took a breath. You breathe your
life in me.
You have been so so kind to me.
Oh, the overwhelming
neverending
reckless love of God. Oh, it chases me
down. Fight till I'm found. Leaves the
99.
I couldn't earn it. I don't deserve it.
Still you give yourself away.
Oh, the overwhelming
neverending
reckless love of God. Yeah.
>> I was your foe. Still your love for me.
You have been so so good to me.
Yeah.
I felt no worth. You paid it off me.
You've been so so kind to me.
Oh, the overwhelming,
neverending,
reckless love.
Oh, it chases me down. fight still I'm
found please 99
I couldn't earn it I don't deserve it
still you give yourself away
all the overwhelming
neverending
reckless love of God
there's no shadow you won't light up
mountain you won't climb up coming after
me.
There's no wall you won't kick down. Lie
you won't tear down. Coming after me.
There's no shadow you won't light up.
Mountain you won't climb up. Coming
after me.
There's no wall you won't kick down.
High you won't tear down. Coming after
me.
Oh, the overwhelming
neverending
reckless love of God.
Oh, it chases me down. Fight till I'm
found. Please
night and I couldn't earn it. I don't
deserve it. Still you give yourself
away.
I'll be overwhelming.
Neverending
reckless love of God.
Here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens. When you need support
or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
Heat. Heat.
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
Hi LC family. Welcome to prayer time. We
want to welcome you all to the prayer
time for today. And I will be your host
Kazia Matanda and we will have our host
Jocelyn and my sister Hadassa.
Michaela's sister is Jocelyn and my
sister is Hadassa. Um, so we're going to
welcome you all. Remember to put your
prayer requests in the chat also along
with your pray
and don't forget to text pray. Remember
to keep praying for those out there in
the LC family around the world. Okay,
Joel, I'm gonna hand it over to you to
do our shoutouts.
Okay. Um, happy Sabbath everyone.
Um, okay. Oh, happy Sabbath. I see you
in the chat. Um, Majesta
and Miss Jerry Harvard. Miss Jerry,
happy Sabbath. And, uh, also happy
Sabbath to Miss Amra and J Ary. And um I
also see happy Sabbath to Terrence. Um
thank you everyone. And yeah,
do you want to say anything?
>> Thank you.
>> So much Jocelyn putting in your praise
reports and we will continue to shout
out to you as we go through. We're gonna
go to our praise reports now. And we
have some powerful praise reports from
different people that have come. And I'm
going to start with a praise report from
sister Lawrence. She says, "Thank you
for praying for my dear friend and
sister Marie An from Sitzerland.
Yesterday she was insulted in public by
someone who attends all the churches.
And she's being harassed by constant
demands from other from another
non-believer who always gets herself
into extricable situations, always with
good reasons and no one else to help. My
friend is getting older and no longer
feels able to face these problems. She's
doing what she can, taking these
situations to heart for months, but
she's not able to say no when she gets
stuck. Lord, intervene. Give her
strength. Inspire her. she no longer has
your peace. Restore her peace and
serenity to her to protect her in the
name of Jesus. Amen. And um historian
says, "Thank you so much for your
prayers. She's just received news from
Mary an lady who insulted her came to
her for reconciliation. Can we say amen
to that?" And the other lady accepted
that Mary Anne wouldn't come today.
Still on an ongoing issue, but we'll
hope that Mary will have strength to say
no when needed. Um she says all of you
thank she says a message to all of you.
Thank you from the bottom of my heart
for my dear ones for your prayers and
those of your friends. Please thank them
for me. It teaches it touches me deeply
and reassures me because I see how much
the Lord loves us even though we even
through people we don't know. Have a
rich blessed and beneficial Sabbath. We
also have another praise report from
Sharon U. Mrs. Sharon Fay Johnson.
Praise God, my vehicle will be fixed and
the warranty will cover all the repairs
with zero deductible. Also, the warranty
will reimburse me back up to $200 in the
towing fees. So, my only out- of-pocket
expense is $50. My my vehicle is
expected to be ready by Friday. Isn't
that amazing? God definitely always has
an answer to our prayers.
Um, we have another one. Praise God. The
doctor's assistant told me that my
mamogram report is normal and to share
to shred that second letter because I
was not supposed to receive a second
letter. Amen. Another one says, "Praise
God. I got a chance to witness my
neighbor's wife witness to my neighbor's
wife about the importance of prayer and
knowing God's word. She was so happy and
I showed her last Sabbath's video." We
have another one. Praise God. She and
her husband offered to drive me about an
hour and a half to Cleveland. um
Minnesota to pick up my vehicle in
Cleveland, Minnesota and not to worry
about paying them gas money for the
ride. Thank you, Lord Jesus. Thank you,
Lord. Thank you all my dear brothers and
sisters for praying with me and for me
to petition at God's throne of grace and
mercy to obtain his righteous favor for
his abundant blessings in Christ Jesus
name. Amen. And amen. Continue to send
in your praise reports. Um, we want to
thank you all for coming and we want to
praise God for these praise reports and
praise him for blessing us in every
single um way of our lives and blessing
us with the opportunity to witness,
blessing him with um helping those to
come for forgiveness and also for those
who weren't able to um put their praise
reports that they will also be filled
with the Holy Spirit and know that God
is there for you and he is constantly
constantly hearing our requests of
prayer towards him. Um I will now have
my um sister read the prayer requests
and um then we will go into intercessory
prayer. Any prayer requests will be
continue to be sent in and we'll
continue to say them.
Uh uh Kzia, could I just add something
really quick?
>> Yeah, go ahead.
>> Okay, so um happy I also see Miss Lisa
Clark and Miss Joanne Steven. Happy
Sabbath. Miss Job happy
to the prayer requests. And as you
continue to receive prayer requests, we
will continue to
to the prayer requests. And as we
continue to receive prayer requests,
we'll continue to say them.
>> Happy Sabbath, everyone.
Um, Rob says, "My great an uncle Kenneth
E. Williams passed away on Thursday and
was found in his car deceased that
evening. Pray for the Kendricks,
Bullsby, and Thompson families in our
time of birth.
We'll be praying for you guys." And
Monip
prayer requests for you guys. And
Monip's
prayer request says for the Holy Spirit
to give us fresh oil for an awakening of
the people of the earth to encounter the
Lord as the days are becoming more evil.
We'll be praying for that
in for our
our churches all living through wars and
conflict. Pray for brother Taj and his
family.
Empty may be from paranoia and mental
confusion. Restore sely and
the year
years
the locust has eaten. Brother Grimson my
wife Muriel struggling with medical
heart condition. We'll be praying for
we'll be prepare we'll be
praying for all of those prayer requests
that keep on coming in. I'm sorry if I
can't say all of them. I do not have the
chat up on my screen. But I pray that
the Lord has received each of those
prayer requests and that he will
continue to
receive for each and every one of us. Um
Justin, are there any more shout outs
you want to give just before we pray?
>> Uh sure. Um I also see there's uh um
flap Rob which um happy Sabbath to you.
And I also see
Jean Jeina Rrower. Is that how you say
it? Um hopefully I said it right. Um
happy Sabbath to you also. And then I
also see Jacqueline Clark. So happy
Sabbath to you was Jacqueline. Um and I
think that's all the shout outs I see. I
um Yeah, I think that's it.
Okay. Um, now we're going to do
intercessory prayer as we finish up our
prayer time for today. Thank you so much
for joining us.
And I will now have my sister pray for
each and every one of the prayer
requests that have been given. All
right, let's pray. Kind and loving
father in heaven, we praise you for
everything that you
That's what
we
more
everyone.
Bye. Happy Sabbath.
Tear
so sweet
to trust in
Jesus.
us to take
him at
his word and
just
to rest
upon his
promise. Yes, Lord. us to know
the saith the Lord.
Jesus.
How I
trust him
and how I prove him
or and
Jesus
preious
Jesus.
Oh, for grace
to trust
him more.
My
hope is built on
nothing less. Yes, God. and
Jesus blood and
righteousness.
I dare not trust the
sweetest frame but holy lean on
Jesus name.
Oh Christ the solid
rock I stand
all the ground is
sinking sand.
All of the ground is
Jesus Jesus
why how we want to trust you.
How we've proved you are and
Jesus
preious
Jesus.
Oh for grace
to trust
him
more.
Oh mighty God. Thank you Lord.
Hallelujah. Forgive us where we have not
trusted you. And may we make a decision
tonight to put our trust.
You
in your
Where can I go from your spirit?
Where can I flee from your presence?
If I go up,
if I make my bed,
if I
if I settle,
even there your hand will guide me.
Your right hand will hold me fast.
If I say surely the darkness will hide
me and the light become night around me,
even the darkness will not be dark to
you.
The night will shine like the day for
darkness is as light to you.
For you created my inmost being.
You knit me together in my mother's
womb.
I praise you because I am fearfully and
wonderfully made.
Your works are wonderful.
I know that full well.
My frame was not hidden from you.
When I was made in the secret place,
when I was woven together in the depths
of the earth,
your eyes saw my unformed body.
All the days ordained for me were
written in your book
before one of them came to be.
How precious to me are your thoughts,
God. How vast is the sum of them.
Were I to count them, they would
outnumber the grains of sand. When I
awake, I am still with you.
Heat.
Good morning everyone. Happy Sabbath and
welcome to Locosc Youth Sabbath. Um
today my sermon is a very special one.
I'll be sharing my personal testimony
and I hope that you'll enjoy it. So,
let's jump straight into prayer and get
started. Father in heaven, I want to um
ask for your presence here right now and
wherever else we are or wherever we may
be watching this. Jesus, I want to ask
that it it's not me speaking today, but
that it's your words coming through me
um like a fountain of fresh water.
Jesus, I ask that this message will
touch the hearts that it needs to touch.
Jesus, please let this message
go through the world and find those that
you prepared it for. In your name, I
pray. Amen.
Okay. If you guys looked at your phone
one day and you saw a text message from
Jesus,
what would you expect him to say to you?
Or if he sat down next to you, what's
the first thing you'd expect him to say?
You know, most of us were like, "Oh,
Jesus is going to say something hopeful
to me or I hope he's going to like
encourage me or something." But did you
know that we as a church in our day and
age actually have a um a message for us
in to our very day and age
and it's not a positive one. Let's go to
Revelation 3 15 and 16 where Jesus says,
"I know your works that you are neither
cold nor hot. I could wish you were cold
or hot. So then, because you are
lukewarm and neither cold nor hot, I
will vomit you out of my mouth."
But this isn't even all. In the
following verses, Christ goes on sternly
detailing the rest of our faults. He's
like, "Y'all are blind and you guys are
you guys are, you know, lacking gold
refined in the fire." And he's like,
"Come into me and buy all these things."
But did you know that we are the only
letter to the church that he doesn't add
anything good? Literally nothing. Like
even Sardis, the church that was like
spiritually dead, like she got like,
"Oh, you know, you have people who are
in in your church and they're still
walking with me." And they got commended
for that. But Leodysia doesn't even get
a single good thing that Jesus, you
know, talks about or mentions. It's just
like all bad. It's like, my goodness,
what's going on here? And it seems like,
well, you know, we in Lord, we try so
hard like every day. It's like, oh, we
want to live godly lives and we put all
this effort into being good and into
being godly and and it's like we don't
even get an E for effort. Like, what is
going on here? What's wrong?
God identifies Leodysia as a spiritually
poor church.
And apparently spiritually poor is worse
than spiritually dead.
God says, "I wish that you were either
cold or hot."
Spiritually dead is good because God can
resurrect.
Spiritually hot is good because you are
in touch with God. You're connected.
but spiritually poor.
It doesn't mean that we're all dead or
we're all in. It means we're just kind
of hanging in the middle somewhere.
There's like a middle ground.
But there is no middle ground. So,
what's wrong? How can we fix this?
You know, as a church, we've got many
outward forms, but we have minimal
inside power.
God wants to fill us,
we his temples with fire from heaven.
But we don't let him. Our faith in him
has made him a God who is so small that
he will fit in our back pocket where he
is the one who created the heavens that
we live under and the earth that we live
on.
And we forget that and we make him so
tiny. And he's like, "Guys,
I just want to exercise my power for
you."
He calls us lukewarm.
You know, it's it's kind of funny
because I like to think of it this way.
How does fire how Sorry, now I gave it
away. But how does water get warmed up?
Well, back in the days of Jesus, you
didn't have anything else except fire
that you could put it on.
So, what does this mean for our lukewarm
state in Lisa?
Does it mean that we have a little bit
of fire?
Yeah, we have a little bit of fire, but
it's not enough to get the water
boiling,
and it's not enough to let the water
cool down.
This is a dangerous state to be in.
Let's keep going.
Leysia is not beyond all hope though.
Even though we have this condition of
not quite dead and not quite alive, God
says, "Hey, you know, if you realize
that you're spiritually poor, we can
definitely work with that." Like if you
get, "Hey, I'm not like out of the
church, but I'm not like in Jesus. I'm
just kind of like in the middle. I'm
like in the church but out of Jesus.
It's like he's like, "Okay, if you get
this, I can work with you." Like I can
work with you. He literally calls us
blessed. Matthew 5:3 says, "Blessed are
the poor in spirit. For theirs is the
kingdom of heaven."
Jesus wants us to realize that we are
spiritually poor
because when we realize this he can
bless us and begin to reveal himself to
us. There's a quote that I really like
from the book Mount of Blessing.
Thoughts from the mount of blessing here
on page seven, paragraph one. It says
that those who know that they cannot
possibly save themselves
or of themselves do any righteous action
are the ones who appreciate the help
that Christ can bestow.
They are the poor in spirit
whom he declares to be blessed.
You know, if today you're feeling
spiritually desolate or you're feeling
spiritually poor and you realize, Lord,
I'm like on the outside of heaven but on
the inside of the church,
that's a good news because you can come
to Jesus the door and be let in.
But you have to realize that you're not
in heaven in heaven
to understand that you need the door.
Let's look at this um this quote from uh
testimonies for the church volume 4.
Inward pity and true devotion are fast
giving place to outward forms.
Pure and undefiled religion is the great
need of our church.
They should make it an individual work
to draw near to God.
Self reigns in the heart instead of
Christ.
Self-will,
self-interest,
envy, and pride shut out the presence of
God.
We really need a door.
Now, let me share a quick illustration.
You know, I've talked about how we have
a lot of outward forms but not much
inside power. I want to share this story
with you. So, you've probably got your
phone like on the coffee table in front
of you or in the car next to you or
wherever you're watching this from. And
you know how dependent you are on this
phone. Like you use it for everything.
Like all sorts of things are really like
you need this phone. Like you can't live
without it. And recently my So this is
the thing about my dad. He has a really
interesting relationship with his phone.
Like he's not dependent on it. Like he
just doesn't use it. So sometimes I use
it for like you know doing school or
like communication. But the other day I
had powered off his phone for bedtime
and the next morning he was like okay I
need my phone. He grabbed it and ran out
for work. And
because
form
And that
question
just
Should we toss out our forms just
because they're not filled with the
power of God?
No, we shouldn't. I mean, I hope you
guys said, "No, my dad should not have
thrown out his phone." That means you
are sane. I'm glad that you said yes.
But um should should we should we throw
out our forms just because they're not
filled with fire? Or should we should we
be like, "Okay, what can we do to fill
this with fire?" Like, "What can we do
to make this effective and powerful and
farreaching and worldchanging?" Because
in essence, this is what our religion
is.
The faith as it tells us in the Bible,
this is not just a oh Lord, I feel good
today kind of faith. No, this is a
radical faith that changes things.
God puts governments in and takes kings
out.
God isn't a wimp.
God does stuff. So, if we see that our
forms are missing God power, we need to
be like, "How can we get God power? How
can we get God power?"
So, at this point, we're probably all
wondering, how do we get God power? How
do we fill our form with fire?
And at this point, I want to share my
personal testimony and my personal
experience of how um I got my form
filled with fire.
So, I grew up as like a fourth
generation Adventist, right? like I'm
very Adventist and I have, you know, I
believe in all the fundamentals and
everything and I'm very solid on them.
And, you know, at 5 years old, I was
like, "Oh, you know, I want to be
baptized." Like, I was basically raised
in like Adventist Amazing Facts media.
So, I'm like, "Oh, I want to be
baptized." You know, and I actually went
to a prophecy seminar they did um live
at our local church at that time and I
made a public decision to get baptized
and a year later I did. But um
I liked reading my Bible. Like I
literally loved reading my Bible. I
still do. Like I read like oh you know
Leviticus and like Deuteronomy, 1 and 2
Samuel, like King David. He's like the
best Bible character ever. Like but um
you know Jeremiah, Isaiah, all these
different Ezekiel like all these books
just like fascinated me and I love the
Bible. So, like I would read it till
like 2:00 a.m. So, but you know, Satan
wasn't happy about that. So, he at like
age 10, I got a toxic infection that
really slowed me down in my spiritual
life. And um
yeah, that was really hard. And I I had
trauma after that for like years, but
God helped me through it and we came
through together. And you know, now I'm
back on track and I'm really thankful to
God for helping me get through that. But
you know, when the pandemic hit, you
know, my family, we were like, well, we
have a lot of time on our hands right
now. So, let's make some changes to how
we use it. So, we just started having
family worship in the morning and in the
evening. and mom and dad stressed
personal worship and um just the daily
surrender, the daily giving over of self
to God and hiding hiding ourselves in
Jesus and wearing the robe of
righteousness.
We were all young back then. We were
like 12 and like I don't know seven and
four. But it was it was really like
life-changing and a lot of things
happened in our family like we had more
peace and it was it was just you know my
siblings and I like we hardly fought
like my mom can testify to that and it
was it was a big change but you know
when the world returned back to normal
kind of the old normal crept back in and
we kind of we drifted a little bit and
we still had like worship every day but
it maybe it wasn't like every single day
of the week. It was like maybe only like
five out of seven. But you know,
things happen in life. Like God knows
that we are butt dust. But definitely he
helped us through that again. But, you
know, after a couple years of just like
like living back in the old carnal way,
it was like
I sat down and I said, "Okay, God,
either you're not working
or I'm not working
because I have no victory." Like,
temptations will come and I will just
like fall into them like it was like a
water slide with soap on it. Like there
wasn't any pause or like because people
will say they'll be like okay think
before you speak and it's like yeah no
that that that doesn't happen like uhuh
that applies to like temptation
generally. It was like no
oh my siblings annoys me. Oh let me snap
out you like and it's like no I didn't
even want to do that. Like what just
happened? Yeah. Stuff like that. And it
was it wasn't fair. Like I was like,
Lord, I didn't even have an opportunity
to even choose. No, I don't want to do
this right now. Like th this can't this
can't be fair. Like if you're a fair
God, I need a fair chance. Like,
you know, like no, that this is
something must be off
because I would have like on again,
off-again victories. It wasn't like I
wasn't a good girl. Like I went to
church faithfully and I did, you know,
Sabbath school and all the right things.
I ate healthy, you know, tofu, broccoli,
all these good things. And um you know,
but but it just there just was something
missing. Like there wasn't there wasn't
the filling in the apple pie. Like it
was just like crust. And I know some
people like just crust, but I was like,
"No, I can't deal with just crust. It's
too flaky. It's too dry." Like
ah it it doesn't work. It doesn't work.
So,
my self-worth because of this, it just
kind of went down into the basement
except it missed the basement and went
straight to the abyss because it was
like, "Yeah, you're like a failure.
You're you can't do this. It's it's it's
all bad. It's all bad bad." I was like,
"Oh, I'm trying in vain and I I can't
get anywhere. My efforts, they're not
doing anything. Like, it's it's just
sometimes." And but I want to be like
good. like I want to be obeying God. And
I'm like, God, what's on? I need help.
And I was like, okay, well, let me go
see what where I can get help. Like, I
want I want help now. So,
I said, "Okay, I'm going to go to
I'm going to go to the church members
and then kind of ask them like, you
know, because like I had questions like
I was like, "Okay, how do I know I'm
saved? How how do I get saved?" like uh
like I didn't even really know what my
question was. I was just like this isn't
working and I need a solution.
I need a solution.
So one Sabbath I sat down in
adult Sabbath school
and I asked a question
and
there was an awkward I mean it seemed
awkward to me. There was an awkward
pause. People just kind of like okay
what is she trying to do? And I was
like, "All right." Um, so I asked my
question and I got like four people
answered and by the time they were done,
I had like seven different answers. And
I was like, "Okay, okay, okay. No, this
is not this is not working. Like I don't
understand." And then I asked like,
"Okay, what do you mean by this and this
specifically?" And they were like, "Oh,
um, this we can't explain this right now
because this would take like way longer
than we actually have time right now."
And I was like, "Excuse me, what? Like,
this is so complicated that you have to
like have a whole other conversation and
like you're going to have to like take
an hour of time to explain this to me.
Like, this is about salvation. Like,
this is a basic thing in our church.
Like, we built like religion is based on
salvation, right?" Like, and I was like,
"No, no, no, no. This this can't be
right. Like, look what's going on here."
And
I was like, "All right,
this isn't working. This is not
working."
So
I told God, I was like, "All right,
Lord.
I'm going to
only read the Bible."
Like, I want my answer from you.
It needs to be 100%
you.
I don't want anybody's opinion,
anybody's
uh thoughts. I want actual truth.
Like I want truth.
And I actually even stopped reading like
any other books on like, oh, how to
overcome temptation or stuff like that
cuz I was like, you know, I've tried all
of this at least once and it's not
really working. Like, okay, it works for
maybe like a month, but then it's like,
I'm too lazy. It's just too much work.
And it's like, well, the Bible says that
the yoke is easy, right? And God's
burden is light. But
that that just wasn't reality for me.
Like, it wasn't light and easy. It was
hard and labor laborious. It was like,
"Oh, I have to do this." It's like, I
don't know if you've ever read like
Pilgrim's Progress, but where Christian
comes to see the lamb at the top of the
hill, he sees the lamb and his burden
just like rolls off down the hill. And I
was like, I'm still carrying my burden.
Like, I can't be like on the right
track. Like, there's got to be something
something different. So, I said, God, I
want you to show me how to be saved.
like you need to figure this out because
I'm kind of done with the church because
it's not giving me proper answers. I
like I need a concrete answer. And I
realized, you know,
they don't even know themselves
concretely.
What's salvation? Like what is like how
do I get saved? For example, like nope,
I don't know. And it's like, okay, like
I guess I have to go to the Bible if I
want to have an answer on this. So I was
like, all right. And what I did was I
told God, all right,
this is going to be like a chat between
you and me, like a text message or like
a messaging platform. And I said, "All
right, like a like a child, you say,
okay, even the children." So I'm like,
"All right, like a child, I'm going to
take the Bible seriously. Like I'm
literally going to take it seriously.
Like I'm gonna believe now that when I
open this book that you can actually
talk to me through it. Like I don't have
to I don't know like go to a Bible study
guide with like you know a trifold you
know those Bible study guides or like a
or a a website or something to figure
out what you actually mean like no no
I'm going to actually
see what do you have to say. So I
started taking his word extremely
seriously and like this is a practical
application in my life like right now
like this text
and
I started expecting real responses like
I had expectations. I was like God I'm
coming to you. I'm telling you Lord I
need this. I'm open your word. What do
you have to say to me? of course within
bounds. But
I was like, I want to know what I need
to do to get saved.
Please show me from your word the way to
salvation.
And when I started reading, I found that
the Bible makes it clear that Jesus is
the way.
I mean we have Acts 4:12 which says
nor is there any salvation in any other
for there is no name under heaven given
among men by which we must be saved
other than the name of Jesus of course
or John 14 chapter John John John John
John John John John John John John John
John John 14:6 where Jesus says I am the
way the truth and the life.
No one comes to the father except
through me.
I am the way,
the truth, and the life.
Jesus invites us to come to the father
through him.
And that was kind of problematic for me
cuz I was like, "All right, I'm going to
take everything like literally within
bounds, of course." And I was like, "All
right, Jesus, I can't walk on you. I
can't walk through you.
This does not make sense. Like, what do
you mean? Like, how do I come to the
father like through you? Like, I don't
know. I can't physically walk like
you're not a pathway, right?" So I was
like, "Hm,
well Lord, I you say that you save and
you invite me to come,
but you know, you you don't live on
earth. You're not physically here. So So
how am I supposed to come to you?"
And I still remember
when God answered that question.
So I sat in church one Sabbath
and I was just I was just done. I was
like, "Okay, okay, no." I was like,
they were preaching and I was like
sitting there screaming inside my head,
"Feed me. Feed me. I need I need
to know that Jesus listens to me." I I
was I was asking God like the classic
question, God, do you even exist?
Are you even real? Are you listening?
Because I need help, but I need it now
or I'm leaving.
And this wasn't because, oh, I wasn't
convinced of the truth. No, the Sabbath
and all the state of the dead and all
these things, the forms are great and we
shouldn't throw them out. But if the
forms aren't filled with fire,
people start asking questions.
And I asked questions and I said, "Okay,
you promised you would lead and guide.
You promised you'd be with us wherever.
So, I need you to answer."
And
I opened my Bible because I was like,
"All right, Lord. time for you to speak.
And I flipped through like something in
I don't know Mark or something and then
I got to Luke
got to Luke chapter 2 verse 49 to 50
where it says
you know the story Jesus is talking in
the temple with the teachers and his
parents are looking for him and he says
when they find him he tells them why
were you searching for me?
didn't you know that I had to be in my
father's house?
But they did not understand what he was
saying to them.
And I remember I got furious cuz I was
like, "Lord, this is the same exact
question like the question they asked
Mary asked Jesus like where were you?
Like didn't you know? I was so anxious."
And Jesus is just like, "Well, didn't
you know where I was? Like I was didn't
you know that I had to be in the
father's house?" I was like, "Lord,
this is the exact question I've been
asking. Like, where were you? Didn't you
Did you have like no empathy that I've
been looking for you like like this?"
Like, I've been agonizing. I've been
like, "Oh, is God even real?" Like, I've
I've been asking these classic
questions, and it's like, "All right,
where's my answer?" And then it comes
around. I flipped to this page, and
God's like, "Why were you searching for
me? Didn't you know I had to be in the
father's house? And I was like, God,
what is the father's house?
That doesn't make sense.
I have the same question and I don't
understand either.
And then another verse flashed through
my mind and I started crying.
Luke 19 46-47
It is written he said to them
that my house will be a house of prayer.
For me personally
this was a
huge answer.
It might seem a little out there the way
I connected these, but to me at that
moment, this was exactly what I needed
to hear. I was like, "Oh my goodness."
Jesus was telling us, you know, he was
like, "Okay, you want to know how to
come to me? Okay, the father's house.
I'm here.
And he was like, "All right, location,
hours,
services,
every day at the temple teaching." You
notice that last part in the slide?
Every day he was teaching at the temple.
Every day
at the temple, the father's house
teaching.
I was like, "This is fantastic. This is
awesome." I was so excited. I was like,
"I found Jesus. I know where he is. He's
in prayer. Like, I can get to him
there." I was like, "Yes, yes."
I was like, "Wow, you actually do still
answer people practically." Like, what?
Cuz I I didn't know that the Bible
worked that way. I I I didn't know. I
was like, "Okay, whatever." And just
read like another story of Noah's arc or
something, you know? I was like, I
didn't know the Bible could apply
personally to your life and that God
could actually speak to you, speak to me
using these ancient words, these ancient
pages, these well, not ancient in my
Bible. I mean, I hope you have a new
one, but you know, just this old old
stories. I was like, "Wow, God is real."
That proved to me God isn't just some
sort of story figure. God speaks and
when you have a question, he answers.
The truth as it is in the Bible is that
if you desire to come to Jesus,
you can come to him in prayer.
You know, I had envy about, you know,
all the blind and sick people and all
these people back in his day because I
was like, well, they could physically
come to Jesus. Like, I can't do that.
That's not fair.
Yeah, you can come to Jesus physically.
You just have to close your eyes and
start praying.
You're there and he's there and you can
talk
whenever you need to. Please, if you're
driving, don't close your eyes while you
pray.
So, apparently
at some point I had sort of formed the
idea in my head that, oh, I need to
repent before I can come to Jesus. If
you have that
misconception,
that's not what the Bible teaches.
Because if you have to repent before you
can come to the house of the father,
that that's not what the Bible says.
It's like nowhere does the Bible say,
"Oh, you must repent before you can come
to Jesus through prayer." You can come
to Jesus if
if you've just committed adultery, if
you've just murdered, like you can go
and ask for repentance because
repentance is a gift. It's not a let me
like try to squeeze it out of myself
like Lord, here's a little bit of
repentance. No. No.
Repentance is a gift and it's not a
prerequisite for coming to Jesus.
But I want to notice espec especially
what the last part of Luke chapter 9 19
46 to 47 says.
It says that every day he was teaching
at the temple.
every day at the temple
teaching.
So I said, "Okay, Lord, I see how it is.
You want me to come every day
to the temple, the father's house, and
you're going to teach me."
I was like, "What are you going to teach
me exactly? What are you going to teach
me?" And I looked at Matthew 11:1 19
where it says
Jesus says, "Take my yoke upon you and
learn from me
for I am gentle and lowly in heart
and you will find rest for your souls."
And I was excited. I said, "Hey, that
actually sounds really good. Like I need
rest for my soul because I'm constantly
just fighting temptation. I'm like day
in day out like 24/7 like oh it just
doesn't stop. I'm exhausted.
I'm exhausted by this. This isn't rest.
This is hard work.
I was like okay
if you want me to come every day to your
temple that's something I can do. I can
I can come and pray every day. You know
that that's something I can do.
So I said, "Okay, I'm going to do this
and I'm going to do it as long as it
takes until I actually receive that
rest." Cuz you said, "I will find rest
if I learn from you. So, I'm going to
keep coming to your classes in the
temple and I'm going to keep listening
and I'm going to keep praying
until I get an answer until I receive
the promised rest because you said so. I
was like, "Okay, God said clear it is.
All right."
And that commitment to start praying
every day and to get in touch with God
every day,
that was actually the real starting
point of my journey. Like all the
frustration before and all of the all of
the fighting and the battles and just
just being discontent, that was kind of
like the precursor to like the real
deal. It was like okay now your
spiritual journey is starting because
you realize all right there's nothing I
can do.
I I can't save myself.
I want to read this
statement from the desire of ages
and it goes like this. It says, "Blessed
are they which do hunger and thirst
after righteousness."
The sense of unworthiness will lead the
heart to hunger and thirst for
righteousness.
And this desire will not be
disappointed.
Will not be disappointed.
Those who make room in their hearts for
Jesus will realize his love.
All who long to bear the likeness of the
character of God shall be satisfied.
The Holy Spirit never leaves unassisted
the soul who was looking unto Jesus.
He takes of the things of Christ and
shows them unto him.
If the eye is kept fixed on Christ,
the work of the spirit ceases not until
the soul is conformed to his image.
I had now learned through experience
that God can and does still speak
through the word of God. It's as real
now as it was back then. It's as fresh
and as relevant to us as he spoke to
Jeremiah, to Isaiah, to David, to
Daniel. This stuff is relevant today and
to you.
When I started holding God accountable
for what he said,
he began to fulfill his promises for me
personally
and I began experimenting with my faith.
I would read promises like Isaiah
55:1 where it says, "So shall my word be
that goes forth from my mouth.
It shall not return to me void.
But it shall accomplish what I please
and it shall prosper in the thing for
which I sent it.
God says the words that he speaks will
not return to his mouth void. That means
the promise will not be left
unfulfilled.
When I read stuff like that, I'd say to
God, "Lord,
Lord, you wrote right here in Isaiah 55
verse 11, you said that your words will
not return to you empty.
You said they would accomplish what you
desire."
That means that your promises about
freedom from sin and your promises about
living a holy life, living a godly life
have to apply to me.
They have to be fulfilled in me.
You said that you're not a liar.
So that means that you're able to
fulfill these promises in me.
do in me according to your promise. My
sanctification
is now your responsibility.
You know that I can't resist temptation.
I've tried. It doesn't work. Sometimes
it does. But sometimes is not enough for
me. Sometimes it's frustrating.
You didn't say sometimes you would
fulfill your promise.
You didn't say sometimes my word shall
return to me not void.
You said it shall.
There's no conditional thing there. It
doesn't say maybe it will or perhaps or
well if you're nice enough. It says it
will. So Lord, I claim this.
Thank you so much.
Another thing that I often prayed during
this journey
was,
"God,
I need you to show me the way.
I want to know you and I want to have a
relationship with you, but I have no
idea how to practically start one.
I have no idea.
you'll have to teach me everything from
scratch.
And I found a response to that prayer in
Exodus
to 14.
Now therefore I pray if I have found
grace in your sight,
show me now your way that I may know you
and that I may find grace in your sight.
And he said, "My presence will go with
you and I will give you rest."
I found that this text was a perfect
reflection and a perfect answer to my
prayer.
God spoke to me personally like he spoke
to Moses.
God would guide me and he would lead me
on my spiritual journey. And best of
all,
he would give me rest, which was exactly
what I needed.
I had finally understood
how to come to Jesus and that by coming
to him and learning from him, I would
find rest.
But I want to mention that just because
I decided to commit to daily prayer.
That did not mean that everything was
smooth sailing. Oh no, no, no, no, no.
There was no flip switch, there was
nothing like that.
In fact, when the initial excitement
wore off, I was like, "Oh, do I have to
do this? I don't want to pray right now.
I don't want to." There was no visible
change. Like nothing happened. Literally
nothing happened.
I still kept consistently sinning and I
kept consistently falling short and it
was really really frustrating and I was
like, "Lord, I'm going to give up on you
because you're not doing anything."
I was an empty form waiting for fire
and fire wasn't coming. So I was like
maybe maybe God is broken or something
like may maybe maybe I
maybe I expected too much.
But that's when I found this verse in
the Bible. Luke chapter 18 verse1 Then
he spoke a parable to them
that men always ought to pray
and not lose heart.
So this parable is actually about the
persistent widow
and she persisted and she persisted
until she got what was just like she got
justice.
She didn't give up till she got justice.
like she didn't. And you can read the
rest of it in Luke chapter 18. But to me
and to my frustration, these words of
Jesus were extremely encouraging.
Extremely encouraging because I was
like, "Ah, the days roll by. I pray
nothing happens. I'm still the same old
same old sinner."
And I made a note to myself during that
time that I'd like to share with you. I
wrote, "I feel like I'm unable to draw
close to God."
Press on. Press on. Push on.
Even if prayers don't seem to help,
Jesus said that it is the thing that
will let you find him. He also said that
we should always pray and not give up.
He wouldn't have said that to us if
prayer didn't sometimes make us want to
give up.
So, push past these feelings and don't
give up praying.
That's what I wrote. Because, you know,
daily prayer,
it's not an easy thing. Why is it not an
easy thing?
because it's dangerous for the devil.
The devil does not want you to contact
his worst enemy. That is absolutely not
what he wants you to do. He's like
everything else but not this.
It was a struggle for me.
Sometimes I would come to God as late as
3 p.m.
3 p.m. in the afternoon. I'd come in
dirty and sweaty from gardening. I was
like, "I feel bad. I haven't prayed yet.
I told God I would, but like
and then I would pray."
And sometimes I would get up at 5:30
a.m. in the morning because I was like,
"Ah, I just need to I will spend time
with God now." I felt like a saint.
And the length of my prayers, they were
not consistent either.
They ranged between 90 seconds and two
hours.
Prayer is not easy, my friends. Prayer
takes commitment.
Do you want to know God
or do you not?
You know these really short prayers,
like 90 second prayers, it's a minute
and a half. I often felt really horrible
about it. But even sometimes about my
two-hour prayers, I'd be like, "This
wasn't a good wasn't a good prayer." Had
quality. Bad quality. Don't lie. We've
all thought about we've all said that
and thought about that about our
prayers. It was just like a bad quality.
But I did never give up praying. I was
like, I'm going to keep going.
The content of my prayers was also
wildly different from day to day.
Sometimes I would pray and it would just
be like a volcano. Like I'd be angry and
I'm like, "Lord, I'm desperate. I need
help. Like you're not answering." Ah.
Other times it seemed my like my prayer
was worse than flat soda. Worse than
flat warm soda.
And it hardly reached the attic.
Like it got stuck on my curtain or
something.
A couple of times I came into my room
with the intention of praying. You know,
I'm going to pray. And I sat down on my
floor and I said, "Dear Jesus," and I
just started sobbing. I was like, "Uh,
crying." I was like, "Prayer is hard."
But, you know, Jesus didn't say that you
have to talk when you come to him. He
just said, "Okay, you can sit. You can
sit in my presence. You can just sit
here and cry.
That's okay.
I'm listening.
Because you know friends, he doesn't
just hear your words. He hears the heart
speaking. He can read those tears. God
can read tears.
God can read silence.
God can read your heart. Even if you
have absolutely nothing to say and
you're just sitting there like, "Lord,
what on earth?"
or Lord, I don't even know.
But you know, more often than not, and I
really don't like to admit this, but
this is what happened. A lot of times I
like most times
I would just sit there and for my bed,
I'd be crouched down and be like, uh,
and I'd be like, I do not want to pray
and I do not want to read the Bible. I
don't want to do anything. I want to go
and have fun. Like, I I don't want to
have anything to do with religion right
now. Like, nothing. Like, I want to
leave.
And I'd be really real with God. I'd
say, "All right, Lord. I have absolutely
no desire whatsoever to pray or to read
or I like I just want to leave. Like I
want to leave. I want to go and move on
with my day and not waste this time.
Like pardon me, Lord, but like I really
don't want to waste the time." And but
you know, I'm here because you said
well because I said that I want to come
to you every single day and I'm not
going to give up until I receive that
rest because I still need that rest.
And even though my heart doesn't feel
anything,
I am willing to be made willing to want
to spend time with you.
like I'm not willing, but I'm willing to
be made willing
to spend time in your presence. So, do
something about it.
Very rarely, I walked out of my room and
felt that I had a decent prayer.
But I did not give up.
I pushed through what often felt like
spiritual fog.
About a month of persistence,
I slowly noticed a difference in me. And
out of all things, my music taste
changed. Out of all things,
it would have never even crossed my
mind.
But I went from listening to pop music
to absolutely loving old-fashioned
hymns.
Old-fashioned hymns.
I'm 15.
But that didn't happen. I didn't like
oldfashioned hymns now because, oh, the
music rhythm is good or the lyrics are
fire. No, no. This was because I had
deep feelings towards God that I didn't
have like the words sometimes to
express. And the text of these hymns,
they were
they would be like a I put my heart on
the copy machine and out came these
lyrics
or not these lyrics, this text. And I
was like, wow, I can relate to this.
Like, this is powerful stuff. Like,
there's actually something in here.
Some of my favorite hymns to this day
are still Nearer My God, to thee.
Nearer, still nearer, I must tell Jesus.
And whiter than snow.
You know, God's priorities for us are
different from what we may expect they
are.
Other people may start noticing changes
elsewhere in their lives, but for me,
music was where I sensed God working
first.
Also during this process
of daily prayer and not giving up until
I received till I received that rest God
promised,
I started confessing sins to people that
I had offended or that I had hurt or
that I had done wrong to.
And don't be fooled, that was not easy.
It was not easy. It was humbling. It was
very humbling. much more humbling than I
anything I have done in my life before
or than much I've done in my life. But
again,
I'd said Jesus, okay, I don't want my
iniquities to separate me from you.
And there's a promise that I would like
to claim. It says, I don't have this on
the screen, but
you can probably Google it. And it says,
I have swept away your offenses like a
cloud and your sins like the morning
mist. Return to me for I have redeemed
you. And I was like, Lord, I really want
to claim that promise. Like I do. So I
was like, okay, I'm going confess.
And then I wanted to understand
surrender.
I wanted to understand what is surrender
and how do I do that?
Because surrender has always been a very
very abstract
topic for me.
It's surrender. It's the same as give
your heart to Jesus. Like wonderful. I
can't just tear out my heart and throw
it into the sky of God. Not how this
works. So what does this mean
practically?
It sounds very nice. Surrender. Give
your heart to Jesus. But like when it
comes down to like eternal life and
eternal death,
how do we surrender? Like does anybody
really know?
And I've heard a lot of advice on
surrender on on how to surrender. But
the answer again, I was like, I need to
find this answer in the Bible because
this is where I want God to, you know,
this is where God speaks and he's spoke
to me before. So I don't think expecting
an answer for him on how to surrender
would be too much. So I was like, okay,
okay,
let me find the answer to surrender in
the Bible. And it came with such a
clarity that I have never heard it
explained before.
One evening I was praying and reading
the Bible. Well, specifically I was
reading in the Gospel of Luke because I
really like Luke, right? Like Luke, ever
since that experience with the father's
house and his answer, I was like, Luke,
this is my this is my favorite Bible
book. And it's the scene of Christ's
last moments, you know, where he speaks
his last words.
Luke 23
46.
Verse 46. And when Jesus had cried out
with a loud voice, he saidf, "Father,
into your hands I commit my spirit,"
"Father, into your hands I commit my
spirit."
And having said this,
he breathed to the last.
And the thought hit me.
The moment Jesus
committed his spirit into the hands of
the father,
he died.
There was no struggle. There was no
heavy labor. He just he just died just
like that.
He breathed his last and was gone.
His spirit didn't linger around or go to
heaven or haunt him or something like
that. No, the whole of Jesus, his body,
it was dead.
Like his spirit had been taken from him.
With a snap of a finger,
he was dead.
God had listened to the plea of his son
and taken his spirit from him so that he
might die. I understood the significance
and maybe you do too, but let me try to
explain it anyways.
You can't say I am going to die now and
then just drop dead.
That's not how it works.
The words alone won't kill you.
The words have no power in them to do
that.
In the same way, in the same way,
Jesus's words alone didn't make him die.
His
words didn't make him die.
The father answered his prayer and
that's when Jesus died. When the father
performed his action
of answering the prayer of Jesus, of
answering the words of Jesus,
Jesus died.
The father's action
took the spirit.
Same with us.
I realized that there is nothing that I
can do or that I need to do to
surrender.
It's not about perfect words.
It's about the request.
Once I ask Jesus to take self,
he takes self from me and he kills it.
That's it. It's It's just gone.
Then he fills the void with his spirit.
When you surrender,
the words of the Apostle Paul become
true.
Galatians 20 Galatians 2 chapter
Galatians chapter 2 verse 20 says,
"I have been crucified with Christ. It
is no longer I who live, but Christ
lives in me.
And the life which I now live in the
flesh or in the body, I live by faith in
the son of God who loved me and gave
himself for me.
I have been crucified with Christ. It is
no longer I who live, but it is Jesus
living in me.
And as I realized that,
the cross became the most beautiful
thing in the entire Bible,
the most beautiful thing in the entire
world.
Because I realized
Jesus's last lesson on the cross
the last lesson on the cross
as he was achieving salvation for us.
His last lesson
was on how to accept
that salvation.
He built a bullwark of temptation
against temptation around me.
Somehow I had intuitively known that a
defense wall must be possible because I
had always tried to build one for
myself. I was like, "Okay, let me put a
stone here and a piece there and like
build it up and mortar and brick and,
you know, just like with discipline or
with with um oh, I'm going to quote this
Bible verse before I s you know, when I
was five years old and before I did some
mischief, I would always quote a Bible
verse to myself. I would say, "Be sure
that your sin shall find you out." And
then I would do it anyway. I was like,
"No, quoting Bible verses doesn't work."
No, no, no. This this this doesn't work.
Be sure that your sin shall find you out
and then do it anyways. Like that that's
just that's hypocritical. Like that that
I don't I don't no this is not my style.
Like I can't just No. Uh-uh.
And I had tried to build a defense wall
against myself using techniques like
that like oh let's sing something. If
you feel temptation coming sing
something. Well, friends, the problem is
when you sense temptation coming or when
temptation is already there, you are in
no mood to sing. You're like, "Oh, I
like this." You're like, "No, I don't
want to sing."
It It doesn't work like that. Like, this
is not reality. It sounds very nice and
maybe it works for some people, but it
didn't work for me and I don't think it
works for every one of you. It's just
frustrating. So, I was like, "Ah, my
wall had holes." Sometimes it would
work, but sometimes it wouldn't. And I
would be like, "Oh, there's an enemy
pouring in." And temptation would
overwhelm me. And it would be like, "No,
no, my wall isn't ready. My my wall
isn't sturdy."
But when I realized
that
self is the problem and Jesus will take
self free of charge without me having to
do anything except ask.
I was like, "Wow,
wow."
I was blown away. I was like, "This
eliminates the problem."
If self is gone, self is the thing that
wanted to do these temptations all that
wanted to act on these temptations all
the time. And if it's just gone, well,
temptation loses its power.
Because now the spirit of Christ lives
in you and you follow the desires of the
spirit.
So when I looked at Jesus on that cross
and I realized, wow, your last lesson
for me, your last lesson for me was how
to accept the salvation
that you were achieving as you died
there.
Wow.
For me?
For me.
You were like, I really want you to
understand. I really want you to
understand this. So the last thing I say
is a lesson
on how to accept this. It's like
God did that for me.
I began to love him immensely. I was
like, oh my goodness, you did that for
me?
Joy poured into my heart as I realized
that
I was in deep awe of Jesus
because he didn't have to do that.
I was deeply fascinated by that moment.
Deeply fascinated.
I felt that I could never never never
never ever pay back all that love he
poured into me. Even if I served him for
the rest of this life and the rest of
eternity, I could never ever pay back a
single bit
what he did. I was like, "This is too
big
and too wide and too deep for me to even
fully comprehend.
Wow.
And that realization was life-changing.
Remember how I told you that I tried to
build up a wall against temptation
and I got frustrated with it?
When I understood how to come to Jesus
and continually
pray, pray every day,
a little wall started to surround me.
Not a visible one. No, no.
A spiritual one.
I had not built that wall. It was
perfect. It had no holes.
It had no gaps.
It was solid.
Through prayer, I had apparently
contacted the master builder and asked
him to come and fix the situation.
He did. He showed up and he built what I
never could have.
I never could have built that. Even by a
whole lifetime of building and even if I
had worldclass discipline
and foolproof strategies, I could have
never made that wall as solid as he did.
Never. It was impossible.
He did and built what I never could
have. And the best part was that I had
no more wall building to do in my own
strength.
My fight was for the continual presence
of God in my life
daily.
He Jesus
did everything else for me.
The entirety
the entirety of salvation
hung on his shoulders alone.
And temptation lost all of its allure.
My desires, they shifted by 180 degrees.
I hated what I once loved and I loved
what I once hated.
And to try and explain what the Holy
Spirit did inside my heart, I'm going to
use the analogy of a parapet.
Have you ever used that word before? Or
have you ever heard that
parapet
part of its definition means low
protective wall or bullwark
fortress and the likes of that.
And for me it was like Jesus had raised
up a low parapet around my heart
all around me and circling.
The job of the parapet was to alert me
when temptation come. Okay came.
If any of you guys have iPhones or eye
devices, you know that little white box
that appears and you can push confirm or
whatever else. Okay. And that's kind of
what the parapit It was like, "Okay, it
gave me like an extra moment, like a
moment of like, all right, let me think
about this. Do I actually want this or
no?" And
that was fair. Like, that was actually
fair. Remember how I told you guys that
before? It was just like, "Oh, I'd slip
into temptation without even thinking
about it. Just like a water slide
covered in soap, like zoom, gone." No,
this was I had a moment to think about
it. I was like, "Do I want this or not?"
It was a moment of thought before I made
my choice.
It was as if the temptation had to stand
outside a door and wait for me to make a
decision. And I could look through the
peepphole and see, oh, who is it? No, I
don't want to let them in. I don't want
to let them in.
Let me give you an example. before the
parapet when one of my siblings would
annoy me. I have two and I love them you
guys.
But you know they they do annoy me
sometimes. They would and they still do.
But when they did I would snap at them
like without even thinking. But with the
parapet
my sibling annoyed me. The temptation to
snap at them would present itself.
But I was able to make a rational choice
about whether I wanted to or not.
Instead of blindly giving in, instead of
blindly sliding into temptation, sliding
into sin,
I was free to choose.
But
it wasn't the parapet alone that
shielded me from temptation.
It would have been somewhat useless if
my desires and attitude towards sin
hadn't changed.
The new heart that Jesus had given me,
complete with new desires
made a huge difference.
When temptation came along, it was like
I was disgusted by it. It's like I'd
look through the people like, "Oh, no,
by no means. Nuh-uh. Go away." Like,
"Jesus, there's someone at the door."
Like, I no, not cool.
Sin was extremely disgusting. Extremely
disgusting. I was like, "Oh, no. How
horrible. How evil. How wicked.
But like I've already stated, the
parapet did not stop me from sinning.
Like I said, I was free to choose.
And I had a new desire that was like,
"No, I definitely don't want to choose
that. No, my goodness." But I was free
to choose.
If I wanted to, I could still give in to
temptation.
And unfortunately, I still did
sometimes.
But when I sinned, it was like I was
stepping over the wall and I'd lose my
peace and I'd lose the comfort I had of
knowing that God was around me. My
connection with God seemed like
interrupted like like you know when you
call somebody and there's like static on
the line and it's like it's like oh
there's something there. What's wrong?
That's what it felt like. I'd regret my
choice almost instantly
and I'd repent. I'd be like, "Jesus, I
didn't want to do that. Would you please
forgive me? I'm sorry. I didn't want
this to separate you from me."
And he'd forgive me. And grace was
granted immediately.
Instantly,
when I knew I was forgiven, I had peace
again. And I felt so thankful for my
advocate, Jesus. I was so thankful. I
was like, "You don't leave me when I
sin.
You're just waiting for me to Okay, when
is she coming? I want to forgive her."
It was just like the words of the
Apostle John in 1 John 2:1.
My little children,
these things I write to you so that you
may not sin.
And if anyone sins, we have an advocate
with the father, Jesus Christ, the
righteous.
And here's another quote from Ellen
White that I think beautifully reflects
the experience of sinning with a changed
heart in the parapet.
We shall often have to bow down and weep
at the feet of Jesus because of our
shortcomings and mistakes.
But we are not to be discouraged.
Even if we are overcome by the enemy, we
are not cast off, not forsaken and
rejected of God. No, Christ is at the
right hand of God.
Who also maketh intercession for us,
said the beloved John, these things I
write unto you, that ye sin not.
And if any man sin, we have an advocate
with the Father, Jesus Christ the
righteous.
And do not forget the words of Christ.
The Father himself loveth you.
John 6:27. He desires to restore you to
himself,
to see his own purity and holiness
reflected in you.
And if you will but yield yourself to
him, he that hath begun a good work in
you will carry forward will carry it
forward to the day of Jesus Christ. Pray
more fervently, believe more fully.
As we come to distrust our own power,
let us trust the power of our redeemer.
And we shall praise him who is the
health of our countenance.
The difference before my experience with
Christ and the Holy Spirit was that it
now took effort to sin. It took effort
to sin.
Whatever had taken an effort to do with
a good attitude, you know, be nice to my
siblings, help my parents, do
schoolwork,
do the dishwasher,
I could do it with a truly happy heart.
A truly happy heart.
and everything that had taken almost no
effort to do
without the change desired. Things like
wasting time or becoming impatient or
being grumpy.
These things all seem foreign to me.
This is exactly what the Apostle Paul is
referring to when he writes in Hebrews
10:1 16.
This is the covenant that I will make
with them after those days, says the
Lord.
I will put my laws into their hearts,
and in their minds, I will write them.
With the new heart, I was able to have a
consistent atmosphere filled with peace,
and I knew that the presence of God was
with me.
That's why I was able to do everything
as unto the Lord. Like it says in
Colossians 3 23. And whatever you do, do
it heartily as to the Lord and not to
men.
Every morning I'd ask Jesus to send me
the Holy Spirit again. And he would.
During that experience,
I understood Jesus so much better.
He had to come to earth and he
experienced the same thing.
He was bombarded with temptations
without breaks. Without breaks.
At least for me, they didn't come up
like all the time, but they came like
boom
boom.
Another temptation.
another temptation. I was like, where
are they coming from? There's like so
many and all the time. Like, oh my
goodness. Of course, the devil sends
these. And it and it made me realize
there actually is a war going on. Like,
the devil's trying to tear down this
wall.
There's a war. There is a war going on
around us.
And
Jesus didn't give in once, not a single
time.
He could have. He had the option to.
This mission on Earth was risky
business.
This wasn't of course I'll do it and of
course it will work. This was a I'll do
it if it doesn't work
dot dot dot.
But he did it. He did it for us. And
Jesus is our example.
As our example, we can do it too. We
will be enabled to do it by his spirit.
We cannot do this of ourselves. With
man, this is impossible. But with God,
all things are possible through him who
believes.
And I want to strongly emphasize at this
point when I was surrounded by the
parapit, I was by no means by no means
perfect.
Neither was I unable to commit sin like
I just shared. I absolutely do not claim
to not have sinned when I have that. I
absolutely claim to have sinned. Yes, I
did sin, unfortunately.
And it nearly tore my heart out when I
interrupted my connection with God.
But he forgave me.
What kept me from sinning at all was the
grace of God alone.
He truly fulfilled his promises in me.
And by now you may be wondering,
is this holy experience? Is this even
like biblical? like this sounds like and
I was wondering myself as I as I was
experiencing this and trying to identify
what was going on and here's what I
found
this idea of a parapet a wall a bullwark
rampart fortification whatever you want
to call it this idea this is a theme
that we often find repeated and enlarged
upon in scripture it's emphasized a lot
for example Isaiah chapter 26
verses 1-3.
We have a strong city
and God will appoint salvation for walls
and bullwarks.
You will keep him in perfect peace whose
mind is stayed on you.
During this experience, I was constantly
thinking of Jesus. Like I was so happy
thinking about him. like he just filled
my heart with joy. I was like, "This is
my redeemer. He saved me.
I only wanted to do what God wanted me
to do because I was like, I just want to
make you happy.
And I know I can never pay it back, but
I just want to I want to do something."
And instead of doing something to be
saved, it was doing something to show my
love.
Instead of doing something to be saved,
it was doing something to show that I
loved him.
Something, just a little thing.
Here's a quote from Steps to Christ,
page 58, that accurately reflects my
feelings toward Jesus. It says, "Who has
the heart with whom are our thoughts? Of
whom do we love to converse to talk
about? Who has our warmest affections
and our best energies?"
If we are Christs, our thoughts are with
him and our sweetest thoughts are of
him. All we have and are is consecrated
to him. We long to bear his image,
breathe his spirit, do his will, and
please him in all things.
This is exactly what it was like for me.
But let's move on to the next scripture
verse. Psalm 91 verse 1:2.
He who dwells in the secret place of the
most high shall abide under the shadow
of the almighty.
I will say of the Lord,
he is my refuge
and my fortress,
my God.
In him will I trust.
He is my refuge and my fortress,
my God.
In him I will trust. And I was indeed
able to say this, he is my refuge and my
fortress. Because I understood that
without Christ, I had nothing to bring.
There was nothing I could put on the
table. I couldn't recommend myself to
God because I was a sinner.
My wall was broken and it was in
disrepair and it was frustrating. But
Jesus
built this wall
around me. And suddenly
God didn't see my broken down wall. He
saw the wall Christ built. And that was
enough.
That was enough.
I want to read another quote quotation
from steps to Christ. This time from
page 69. It says, "Many have an idea
that they must do some part just like
one little part of the work alone. They
have trusted in Christ for the
forgiveness of sin, but now they seek by
their own efforts to live right.
But every such effort must fail.
Jesus says
without me he can do nothing.
Our growth and grace, our joy, our
usefulness all depend upon our union
with Christ.
It is by communion with him daily,
hourly, by abiding in him that we are to
grow in grace.
He is not only the author but the
finisher of our faith. It is Christ
first and last and always.
He is to be with us not only at the
beginning and at the end of our course
but at every step of the way. David
says, "I have set the Lord always before
me because he is at my right hand. I
shall not be moved."
Temptation didn't have the power to move
me,
but I had the power to let it choose to
move me. I had the power to choose if I
would be moved by it, but it didn't have
the power to move me. And why?
Because self,
when self had the power to choose, self
would always choose temptation. Because
selfishness is sin.
And sin begets sin.
Beget sin begets sin. And sin separates
you from the only power that can help
you overcome that can that can resist
that for you.
Also
Psalm 62 verse 6 resonated with me. It
says he only
he
only
is my rock and my salvation.
He is my defense. I shall not be moved.
Again, here we see the pattern repeated.
We shall not be moved if he only
is our rock and our salvation.
you know, in Friday Night Lights, which
we have every Friday night at 8:00 PM
Eastern Standard Time. I just want to
make a little bit of like a an ad here
for Friday Night Lights. Awesome.
Teenagers, if you're listening, please
stop by. Amazing. And Miss Jerry,
we started studying Psalm 23. And
we started with the first verse and we
got not even past the first two words.
The Lord, you know, the Lord is my
shepherd. I shall not work. We we we
started with the Lord. We did not move
past for like an whole hour and a half.
I feel the same way about Psalm 26:6. Uh
Psalm 62:6, pardon. He
only.
He only. I could just go on and on about
he only. It's not he only and a little
bit of us in the background in his back
pocket. No, no, no. It's he only.
Not well half him and half me. No. He
only.
Not some of his effort and some of my
effort and maybe a little bit of my
dogs. No, he only is my rock.
and my salvation.
He is my defense. I shall not be moved.
As I already mentioned, sin became more
disgusting to me. Did not move me
anymore.
And I wanted to have nothing to do with
sin. I was like, "No, this is bad. This
is exactly what put my savior on the
cross. I don't want this."
here in one of my favorite books um
thoughts from the mount of blessing page
um 118 paragraph 3 we can read about the
experience
that I had the only safeguard against
evil I just love how she says the only
safeguard here because we think well
sometimes we can build a little bit of a
safeguard up ourselves it's like okay
well maybe if I quote scripture if I
quote the right verse or if I sing the
right song Maybe I can like No, she's
like the only safeguard against evil.
The only safeguard against evil is the
indwelling of Christ in the heart
through faith in his righteousness.
It is because selfishness exists in our
hearts that temptation has power over
us.
It is because selfishness exists in our
hearts. That temptation has power over
us.
But when we behold the great love of
God,
selfishness appears to us in its hideous
and repulsive character.
And we desire to have it expelled from
the soul, cast out, thrown out,
spring cleaning.
As the Holy Spirit glorifies Christ, our
hearts are softened and subdued.
The temptation loses its power and the
grace of Christ transforms the
character.
None of what I described that took place
in my life was my own dealing. None of
it.
None of it.
None of it was my own.
I know that it was the Holy Spirit
working in me. I know that it was by the
grace of Christ alone.
I know that it was because of his
sacrifice, because of what he did,
because of his grace and his mercy.
That's why this happened. This was not
this had nothing to do with me. This was
all Jesus. This was all Jesus.
He changed my desires and my feelings
about sin.
And you know in Galatians we're given
the promise about the Holy Spirit. You
know that by the help of the spirit we
will no desire we will no longer desire
the fleshly things
the things that our old self wanted and
desired. It says in Galatians 5:16,
"I say then, walk in the spirit
and you shall not fulfill the lust of
the flesh.
You shall not fulfill the lust of the
flesh if you walk in the spirit."
This parapet around my heart
that Christ and his love built for me
was supernatural.
There was nothing human about it.
Because with man, this is impossible.
But with God, all things are possible.
And God is just as powerful now and
today and tomorrow as he was 1,000 years
ago, 2,000 years ago, 5,000 years ago.
But I want to mention one thing,
something that really surprised me about
this parapet that Christ built.
Jesus did not throw out the old stones I
had laid.
He didn't throw them out. That surprised
me.
Every stone I had set,
every carnal effort I had put into being
a good Christian
was valuable.
It was truly valuable
because everything I had avoided and
everything that I had just done out of
my own power to be right, to live right,
anything I had built up,
anything that I had pounded down, every
good habit I had adopted, every doctrine
I had kept,
this all was a blessing.
Every single thing was a blessing. And I
remember regretting that I didn't do
more because now
I had to
h let Jesus build the foundation for
that up in me. And it was just easier to
have the old forms because now the
forms, they were filled with fire
and they were extremely useful to Jesus.
I want to remind you of the phone
analogy again.
Just because the phone isn't turned on
and nobody can reach you doesn't mean
that you throw it in the garbage.
You know, you'd be quite insane if you
did that.
You'd be out of your mind because why?
You just have to turn the phone on.
That's exactly what it's like with the
fire with with the forms, pardon. Just
because the forms have no fire doesn't
mean we should toss them out the window.
By no means.
We ought to keep those and build on them
until we receive that fire from on high
because we will be blessed.
So instead of throwing them away,
let's ask Christ to connect our forms
with the fire. Then they can become
useful tools for him and his glory.
So unfortunately,
the parapet and the new heart
aren't permanent.
This is not a once-s saved always saved
situation. This is a by daily prayer by
hourly prayer by continuation in prayer
by remaining connected to God.
This is how this is maintained.
You can buy a car and you can have a
brand new car, but if you never get the
oil change, if you never do anything
anything to do to fix it, to maintain
it, well, eventually it's going to break
and you're just going to have a a
useless piece of metal sitting in your
garage.
If you don't maintain your connection
with Christ, the parapet and the new
desires will fade and self will return.
I made that mistake
and I deeply regret it.
I deeply regret it.
I let my focus drift back to my own
works
and the parapit faded away.
I am praying and retracing my steps.
retracing the steps that I just shared
with you all. Daily prayer,
letting Christ teach me in his school.
But I know
that the power that
that he exercised then is still
available to me and to you.
It's still available and hope is not
lost.
So
coming back to where we started out,
what's the solution to our spiritual
desolation?
If we want to see change in our
spiritual condition, we need to learn to
rely 100% no 1,000%
on Jesus. We must focus on Jesus.
Jesus alone.
Jesus
alone.
We need to pray to God first
individually
and then together for grace to shift our
focus from our forms
to our creator who can fill this with
fire.
I want to
quickly pivot to the story of Barnameus.
And I don't have the text reference for
it, but you all know how Bardeameus
yelled out to Jesus. He sat on the road.
He was blind. Blind Barameus.
And when Jesus came by and he realized
what was happening, he was like, "Jesus,
son of David, have mercy on me.
have mercy on me. Everyone's like, "Hush
hush, you're too loud." Like, goodness
gracious. Like,
he's not gonna pay attention to you
anyway. He's just like, he's like, he
cried all the louder. The Bible says,
"Jesus, son of David, have mercy on me.
Have mercy on me."
Who else in the Bible
cried out to God, "Have mercy on me."
It's in Luke 18 verse three. And the tax
collector standing a far off would not
so much as raise his eyes to heaven.
But he beat his breast saying, "God, be
merciful to me a sinner.
Be merciful to me a sinner."
It all comes back to Leodysia.
It all comes back to us again.
We must understand our blindness
just like Bardameus understood it. He
didn't sit there and was like, I can see
the trees. When he really couldn't.
He was like, I know I'm blind and I know
I need help and there's someone passing
by who I know can help. I'm not going to
stop asking.
I'm not going to stop crying out until
he answers me. Even if circumstances,
even if everybody around me tells me
it's useless, he'll never listen. I
won't stop.
I won't stop.
When we realize our spiritual blindness,
selfishness, and sinfulness,
Jesus can work with us.
Jesus can finally work in us to do
the good things he wants to do in us. He
can finally work in us to will and to do
the good things according to his
pleasure. Let's look at Philippians
chapter 2:13 on the screen. For it is
God who works in you both to will and to
do for his good pleasure. What does it
say? It doesn't say, "Oh, well, maybe
it's God and maybe it's me or we really
don't know who it is." It says, "No, for
it is God." Very simple. God works in
you both to will and to do for his good
pleasure. So, let me tell you something.
If it is actually God who works both to
will and to do. Well, the doing is one
part that's like that's its own thing.
But the willing,
if you're like, well, I kind of know
that I'm spiritually poor and that I'm
kind of know I have a little bit of a
hunch and like I've been told a lot, but
I don't really like feel it. Like not
really.
Don't feel like this message isn't for
you because God will will in you.
God is going to will in you to want to
do the good things. God doesn't give up
on you just because you don't feel like
it or just because you you don't have
that urgency. In fact, that's why he
sent the letter to Loudest Yak. He's
like, "Guys, hey, you know, there's a
problem. I'm going to make you aware of
it.
We need to ask God to help us realize
our spiritual poverty.
To help us realize that our works are
worthless when not connected to his
power.
To help us realize and understand how we
can connect to his power.
Back to the story about Armmesus. He
didn't first ask
for deliverance from his inability.
He asked for mercy first.
Then when he stood in front of Jesus and
he was
there with Jesus an arms length away
probably and Jesus asked him what do you
want me to do for you Bararddmus? He was
like Lord I want to see. I want to see
Lord
I can't see Lord I realize it and I
can't do anything about it. There's
nothing I can do. I've tried.
I've used herbs. I've gone to the
doctor. I've tried. I can't do anything
about it. Will you please heal me?
And Jesus said,
"Your faith has healed you. Go. Your
faith has healed you." I always looked
at that story. I was like, "What? Your
faith has healed you." What did What did
Barnameus do? He faith.
He just kept yelling. That's all he did.
And I realized,
wow,
when we just keep praying without giving
up, without giving up on God, without
stopping until we get his presence,
until we get the rest he promised, he
calls that faith.
Jesus calls
that
faith.
Are you crying out for Jesus's mercy
today?
Don't get discouraged, though. The devil
is going to try to keep you from calling
out to Jesus because, like I said, it's
dangerous for him. He definitely does
not want you to get in touch with Jesus
because getting in touch with Jesus
means that you're getting out of touch
with him and his temptations will lose
power. It's not a well they might or
well if you know maybe not for me. No,
it's they will they will lose tempt they
will lose power over you. And he's like
no this is not what we want.
I experienced a lot of doubts and was
fighting a lot of lies in my head about
oh you can't come to Jesus because of
this and you can't pray because of that
and so and so. And I just want to like
like tell you like a couple of these
lies because I feel like it's really
helpful to know that someone else has
gone through this and that someone and
that there are like answers to this and
how to not give up. And here's number
one the number one of the devil's lies
that he will tell you. He'll say you are
too sinful to come to God.
Friends, this is absolutely not true.
He'll be like, "Well, God won't accept
you because," and he'll quote the Bible.
He'll say Isaiah 52:2, "Your iniquities
have separated you from your God and
your sins have hidden his face from you
so that he will not hear." Guys, this is
true. But it also says that whoever
confesses their sins to him, he is
faithful and just to forgive them.
Don't be fooled. The devil can and still
does quote the Bible for his purposes
just like he did in the desert with
Jesus. He quote he quote the Bible. The
devil can quote the Bible. He knows how
to get to you.
But Jesus quote quote quoted the Bible
back.
The devil is good at that.
He's in the business of misrepresenting
the creator.
But praise the Lord that we like Jesus
have proof of God's love that say no
I will forgive you. Here Isaiah 44 verse
22 says I have blotted out like a thick
cloud your transgressions and like a
cloud your sins. Return to me for I have
redeemed you. In John 6:37,
"All that the Father gives me will come
to me, and the one who comes to me, I
will by no means cast out." By no means.
1 Timothy 1:15. This is a faithful
saying and worthy of all acceptance,
that Christ Jesus came into the world to
save sinners, of whom I am chief.
Romans 5'8, but God demonstrates his own
love towards us that in while we were
still sinners, Christ died for us. While
we were still sinners, see that lie you
loses his capability. Right there it
says while we were still sinners, Christ
came into our presence. So why couldn't
we come into Christ's presence while we
are still sinners? Lie number two, you
can't go to God right now cuz you just
sin and it's still fresh.
I mean, that is just ridiculous. But I
still fall for it. I still fall for like
oh lord.
I can't really come like I have to do a
little bit of good to balance it out.
That is absolutely ridiculous.
This one is actually like two lies in
one because number one he says you're
too sinful to come to Jesus and number
two he gets you to focus on your works.
You're too sinful to come to Jesus and
he gets you to focus on your works.
But I want to ask you to think back to
the thief on the cross.
Did he have any time to do good works
before Jesus said, "I'll be with you and
you'll be with me in paradise." No, he
had no time to do good works. He died.
He died. He had no chance to do good
works.
Here's a quote that I found helpful.
It's from Ministry of Healing. Many who
have been overcome by temptation are
humiliated by their failures and they
feel that it is in vain for them to
approach unto God. But this thought is
of the enemy's suggestion.
When they have sinned and feel that they
cannot pray, tell them that it is then
the time to pray. Ashamed they may be
and deeply humbled.
But as they confess their sins, he who
is faithful and just will forgive their
sins and cleanse them from all
unrighteousness.
Line number three. This one was also
somewhat difficult for me especially in
the beginning because I would keep
getting distracted.
You keep getting distracted or thinking
sinful thoughts while praying. God can't
listen to prayers like that.
That is not true.
Here's a a quote from the book Prayer
and it says, "We are not to be so
overwhelmed with the thought of our sins
and errors that we shall cease to
prayer." Pray.
Some realize their great wickedness,
their great weakness and sin and become
discouraged.
Satan casts his dark shadow between them
and the Lord Jesus, their atoning
sacrifice. They say it is useless for me
to pray. My prayers are so mingled with
evil thoughts that the Lord will not
hear them.
These suggestions are from Satan. In his
humanity, Christ met and resisted this
temptation, and he knows how to sucker
those who are thus being tempted.
In our behalf, he offered up prayers and
supplications with strong crying and
tears.
Also, I would fall asleep during prayer
a lot. Oh, it would happen a lot a lot.
And I felt horrible about it because I
was like, "Oh, um, you know, I shouldn't
be doing this. It's not
it's not what I want. I really want to
spend time with God and I don't want to
spend time sleeping. Like, I just want
to spend time with God." But you know
what? I realized that if I were a parent
and my child were wanting to spend time
with me
and they fell asleep,
I would not get mad at them. I would
absolutely not get mad at them.
And that understanding helped me in the
beginning. And it soon I didn't, you
know, I didn't fall asleep very much
during prayer anymore because it just
became so important to me.
But no matter what kinds of lies the
devil will tell you to try to keep you
from God,
don't believe him. Believe God.
Remember that Jesus is waiting for you
with open arms
to welcome you home into the kingdom of
heaven.
Don't give up hope even when everything
seems hopeless around you.
So at last family,
brothers and sisters,
I want to make an appeal to you
based on the promises of God
and my personal experience.
I can testify that there is a higher
dimension to our faith than we may have
previously known.
There is an experience with God
available to us today.
Today,
an experience with God that will
transform us.
and by the power of the Holy Spirit,
transform us into his likeness and
remove the bondage of sin and temptation
over us.
The time is here.
God is waiting for us to take hold of
his promises in prayer, to search the
scriptures for more light, and to not
let go until we get an answer from
heaven. Don't let go until you get an
answer from heaven.
Let us wrestle in prayer like Jacob, not
giving up until he blesses us.
Tell God, let us tell God that we will
not relent.
We will not relent until he gives us the
rest he promised in his word. We will
not relent
until we receive the fire promised from
on high.
Until we receive the parapet.
It's available to all those who persist.
Let's keep coming back into his presence
through earnest heartfelt prayer. Let's
stay there.
Let us read his promises back to him.
Let us believe with all our heart
and not stop coming back until we get an
answer.
We are allowed to see it, my friends.
We are the last church.
We will see Jesus come in the clouds of
heaven. Do you believe that
Christ has sent us this letter of
correction? Because the time is short
and he's already at the door. He's
already knocking.
He's not coming out from the car walking
up the side. No, he's already at the
door. He's ringing the doorbell. He's
knocking. He's here.
We will see Christ return in the clouds.
Will your form be empty
or will it be on fire?
I urge you to make your choice today.
Will you ask God
to give you the parapet of his presence
or will you deny the power
and sink back into the fireless forms?
The choice is ours and the choice is
yours.
Let's pray together.
Father in heaven,
I pray that this message and this appeal
will reach hearts
that have never been touched by your
mercy before.
I pray that your words
will plant a seed that will grow and
grow until we receive the rest you've
promised.
Lord, give us grace.
Give us grace to keep seeking you out,
to keep crying out like Barardeameus,
Lord, have mercy on me, a sinner.
Lord, we ask
for the persistence.
We ask for the commitment
and we ask for the fire.
Fill
our temple with the spirit.
Fill our forms with the fire.
God, we believe that you're coming soon
and we believe
we believe in your power to transform
us.
You said, "Lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil." And Lord, we
believe that you can deliver us from
evil.
We pray in your name right now and in
your power
that you will give us this experience
that you will give us a living faith
experience
that we can
live our religion and that the fire can
spill out and spill over and create a
wildfire that will rage throughout the
whole earth. Because then we know then
the end will come and we will see you
and we will get to go home.
Jesus build up the parapet around us.
Take self and kill it.
We ask all these things in the powerful
and lovely name of Jesus.
Amen.
I'm inviting you now to Afterglow where
I will see you in just a minute and I'm
looking forward to see you there. And
now as we listen to one of my favorite
songs, I must tell Jesus,
I want you to think about this.
Will you ask God to give you the parapet
of his presence? Or are you going to
deny the power and sink back into
fireless forms?
Amen.
I must tell G
such
all of my trials
I cannot bear
thee. Peace
burdens alone.
In my distress,
he
kindly will help
me.
He ever loves
and
cares for his own.
Oh,
he'll never leave me nor forsake me.
He's right there by my side.
>> You're never alone. You're never alone.
Alone.
My every need he supplies.
My father cares. That's why I alone. I
don't have to worry. I don't have to
worry.
If you
have some
problems
in your life that you can't solve,
just remember
the one who knows all.
And he's right there when you call.
When you come,
I'm still
all of my trials.
Oh, I cannot bear
these
birdens alone.
In my distress,
he
kindly will help
me.
He ever loves
and
cares for his own. He'll never leave or
forsake you. He's right there by your
side. My every need he supplies.
My father cares. That's why.
>> You don't have to worry. No.
>> Your burdens you won't bear alone. Your
burdens you won't bear alone.
>> Even in your darkest night.
>> Even in your darkest night,
>> he's trying to be a guiding light. Ooh.
You don't have to worry. No.
Your burdens you won't bear alone. Your
burdens you won't bear alone. Even in
your darkest night. Even in your darkest
night.
>> Sure to be a light. Ooh.
>> Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.
Heat. Heat.
That
was